合作翻译    风里漂流  麥尼芽
失 控 玩 家
这里是自由城
This is Free City.
看看这个家伙 他是墨镜家伙的一员
Look at this guy. He's one of the sunglasses people.
而戴墨镜的人都是英雄
And the people who wear sunglasses are heroes.
他们做事我行我素 并且主宰着这个城市
They have a devil-may-care attitude and they run this town.
你真性感
You are so hot.
哦 我知道
Oh, I know.
看到了吗 那根本不是他的车
See? That's not even his car.
也不是他的妻子
Or his wife.
戴墨镜的人可以做任何他们想做的事
For the sunglasses people, they get to do anything they want.
他们执行各式各样的任务
They go on all sorts of missions.
他们有很酷的发型 很酷的衣服
They got cool hair, cool clothes.
法律对他们来说没什么意义 更像是温和的建议
I mean, laws aren't really laws to them. They're more like mild suggestions.
就像 我不觉得他会归还那辆车
Like, I don't think he's gonna return that car.
或是那位可爱的女士
Or that nice lady.
明白了吧? 这就是英雄
See what I mean? Hero.
我叫盖伊 我住在天堂里
My name is Guy, and I live in paradise.
早安 小金
Good morning, Goldie.
我这辈子都生活在自由城
I've lived here in Free City my whole life.
我有一个最好的朋友 有一条金鱼 而且我还在银行工作
I've got a best friend, I've got a goldfish, and I work at the bank.
一个男人还能想要什么呢
What more could a guy want?
周日阳光明媚 街上只有零星的车辆
Sunday should be warm and sunny with just a scattering of drive-bys.
这是去海滩的好日子 但不是杀手海滩
Great day for the beach, but not Hitman's Beach,
那里正遭失窃炮艇的地雷和高口径火力扫射
which will be mined and sprayed with high-caliber fire from a renegade gunship stolen by...
每天早上 我新的一天始于
And every morning, I start my day
一杯世界上最美味的咖啡
with the most delicious coffee in the whole, wide, whole world.
中杯咖啡 加奶油 两块糖
Medium coffee, cream, two sugars.
你真懂我
You know it. Mmm.
嗯
Mmm!
真是出乎意料的烫
That is unexpectedly hot.
天啊 太好喝了
Jeez, that's good.
那感觉就像是在嘴里开了苞一样
It's like losing my virginity, but in my mouth.
谢谢你这充满爱心的咖啡
Thank you for making this with such love.
不客气
You're welcome.
约翰尼警官
Officer Johnny!
祝你过得愉快 盖伊
Have a good one, Guy.
别有不错的一天 要有很好的一天
Don't have a good day, have a great day!
什么鬼
Hold the fudge.
你是说没人把那些坏男孩买走吗 我今天就要买下来
You mean to tell me that nobody snabbed up those bad boys? Today is the day.
-和其他日子一样  -我会回来买的
- Like every other day. - I'll be back for those.
哦 差一点
Oh! So close.
这是有史以来最棒的一杯咖啡
Mmm! This is the greatest cup of coffee of all time.
我想为此写首歌
I wanna write a song about it.
我想用我的身体随着那首歌起舞
I wanna dance to that song with my body.
我爱我的生活
I love my life.
找到自己的路 然后一直走下去
There's something about finding your lane and just staying in it.
这就是为什么人们叫它们舒适区 这太舒服了
That's why they call 'em comfort zones, they're so damn comfortable.
哦 乔
Oh, Joe!
又是周一了对吧 乔?
Mondays, am I right, Joe?
-你说对了 盖伊  -是啊
- You said it, Guy. - Yeah.
在自由城 我有我需要的一切
In Free City, I have everything I need.
别有不错的一天... 要有很好的一天
Don't have a good day... have a great day.
谢谢你
Thank you.
小心
Take care.
除了一件事
Except one thing.
看起来很开心
Seem happy.
不用担心 盖伊 你会找到另一半的
Oh, come on, don't worry about that, Guy. You gonna find someone.
我没事 巴迪
Oh, it's okay, Bud.
感觉我一直都在寻找她 你知道吗
Feel like I've been looking for her forever, you know?
也许我注定不会找到吧
Maybe it's not meant to be.
全都趴下
Everybody down on the ground!
-我知道我要找什么样的女人  -让我猜猜
- I know the woman I'm looking for. - Oh, let me guess.
-有着另类幽默感的女人 -幽默感
- A woman with an offbeat sense of humor. - Sense of humor.
喜欢愉悦的流行歌曲
An obsession with feel-good diva pop.
流行音乐 是的 就是她
Diva pop. Yes, that's her.
她在我脑子里占了个地方 不肯搬走
She's rented space in my brain and she won't move out.
你知道吗 我不想让她这么做
And you know what? I don't want her to.
好吧 你猜怎么着 她既不搬进来也不搬出去
Well, guess what? She won't move either in or out.
你知道为什么吗 因为她根本不存在
You know why? 'Cause she doesn't exist.
-她只是个幻想 都是幻想  -这很残忍 你太残忍了
- She's just a fantasy. It's a fantasy. - That's cruel. You're cruel.
-你太坏了  -我是实话实说
- You're being rotten right now. Rotten. - I'm being real.
没有人想当英雄 这一切很快就会结束的
Nobody try to be a hero. This will all be over soon.
下班后在海滩上喝啤酒怎么样
So how about it? Beers on the beach after work?
我们下班后当然要去海滩上喝啤酒
Of course we're going for beers on the beach after work.
这让我很高兴
That makes me so happy.
我也是
Me too.
你那有什么
What have you got?
秘密关卡的证据 这就是你想要的 对吧
Proof of a secret level. That's what you're looking for, right?
你有录像还是截屏
You got a video or a screen grab?
都没有 但我知道谁有
Nope. But I know who does.
想知道我怎么对付那些浪费我时间的人吗
Wanna know what I do to people who waste my time?
哦 看来你想要玩一玩
Oh, wow. Ooh, someone wants to play.
你真的是英国人 还是用了变声器
Hey, you really British, or is that an accent filter?
因为我们或许可以见个面
'Cause maybe we could meet up later.
我对你妈妈的地下室没有兴趣 谢谢
I don't have a burning desire to see your mum's basement, thanks.
开玩笑 是吗?
Got jokes, huh?
我有张地图 上面有他藏身处的位置
Well, I got a map, shows the location of his stash house.
不知道你要怎么进去
Don't know how you'll get in,
但你如果想进去 56号视频或许会让你感兴趣
but if you do, clip 56 might interest you.
现在 我有一个问题
Now, I got a question.
这个视频到底有什么特别
What's so special about this video clip anyway?
特别的是我杀了问这个问题的人
What's special is I kill people who ask questions about it.
我明白了 乐趣 是啊那很有趣
Mmm, I see. Fun. Yeah, that's fun.
该死 姑娘 你真暴躁
Damn, girl, you're so feisty.
但说真的 这是为了钱还是只是一种体验?
But seriously, is it loot or is it just the experience?
这些都是问题
Those are questions.
你看到上一个劫匪穿的运动鞋了吗
Did you see the sneakers on that last robber?
两点半那个吗
The 2:30?
不 是4点钟的那个
No, the 4:00.
四分之三高统鞋 华丽的泡沫鞋底
The three-quarter high-top, gorgeous foam soles.
他踩在我脸上时 我几乎感觉不到
I could barely feel it when he stepped on my face.
-天哪  -哇
- Oh, man. - Wow.
没有什么比大城市的生活这更好的了
Life in the big city. Ain't nothing like it.
给我
Give it to me!
看起来要下雨了
Looks like rain.
有人看见我的猫了吗
Has anyone seen my cat?
盖伊 大家都这么说
You know something, Guy, people say it all the time,
就像 "盖伊比我认识的任何人都更擅长用脸被鞋砸"
like, "Guy can take a shoe to the face better than anybody I know."
当你把它放在这句式时 就变得不像是被一只鞋砸脸
I mean, when you put it on there, you act like it's not a shoe in your face.
别有不错的一天 要有很好的一天
Don't have a good day, have a great day.
喜欢这首歌
Love that song.
这句是新的
That's a new one.
嘿
Hey!
就是她
That's her.
哪个她
Her who?
我的梦中情人 巴迪
That's my dream girl, Buddy.
她竟然存在
She exists.
-我要去和她聊聊  -停停停停
- I'm gonna go talk to her. - Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
等等 伙计 她戴着墨镜
Wait, man. She's wearing sunglasses.
所以呢
So?
什么 “所以呢”?
Whatcha mean "so?"
戴墨镜的人不跟我们这些人说话
So, people with sunglasses don't talk to people like us.
-你知道的  -我得试试
- You know that! - I gotta try.
盖伊 盖伊
Look, Guy! Guy!
盖伊 在海滩上喝啤酒怎么样
Guy! What about beers on the beach?
打扰一下
Excuse me!
嘿
Hey!
自由城2...即将到来
Coming soon... Free City 2!
更大 更坏 更激进的
Bigger! Badder! Radder!
自由城2 大屠杀
Free City 2: Carnage.
今天预订并获得额外的犯罪礼包
Pre-order today and get the bonus Mayhem Pack.
你玩完了吗
You done?
对不起 你要关门了吗
Sorry. Are you closing?
是的
Yes.
我们平常不会把椅子放在桌子上
We usually don't put the chairs on the tables,
一小杯咖啡坐四小时的女孩
one-small-coffee-over-four-hours girl.
你真的很喜欢那个游戏是吧?
You really like that game, huh?
我12岁的侄子都上瘾了
My 12-year-old nephew's addicted.
似乎每个人都很沉迷这游戏
Seems like everyone's obsessed with it.
哦 自由城? 啊 不是
Oh, Free City? Ah. No.
我要起诉出版商 而我需要的证据就在游戏里
I, uh, have a lawsuit against the publisher and the evidence that I need is in the game.
-然后我的代码…  -哦…我真希望还没要关门
- So then I had my codes... - Oh... I wish we weren't closing
这样我就能听到更多了
so I could hear more about this.
早安 小金
Good morning, Goldie.
中杯咖啡 加奶油 两块糖
Medium coffee, cream, two sugars.
其实 我今天想尝尝卡布奇诺
Actually, I think I'd like to try a cappuccino today.
哦 “卡布奇诺” 我喜欢说这个词
Ooh. "Cappuccino." I enjoy saying that.
就像字母组成的瀑布
It's like a waterfall made of letters.
不好意思?
Excuse me?
我想尝尝卡布奇诺
I'd like to try a cappuccino.
-有请 -但你该要一杯中杯咖啡 加奶油和两块糖
- Please. - But you get a medium coffee, cream, two sugars.
这是你该得到的 也是每个人都会得到的
That's what you get. That's what everyone gets.
每一天 都是这样
Every day. Always.
-好吧,我…  -有人要被枪击了
- Well, I... - Somebody's about to get shot.
约翰尼警官
Officer Johnny.
我只是想尝试些不一样的东西
I just thought I'd try something different today, you know?
随便什么都好
Whatever. Right? Yeah?
嗨
Hi.
哈 我只是想让你保持警觉
Ha! I'm just keeping you on your toes.
请给我咖啡 加奶油 两块糖
Coffee, cream, two sugars, please.
我在开玩笑
I'm joking.
让你保持警觉 我是在开玩笑
Just keeping you on your toes. I was kidding.
他只是在开玩笑
He was just kidding!
你以为我会夺去你的咖啡艺术吗
Oh, you think I'd deprive myself of your baristic artistry?
不可能 不可能
No way, no how.
嗯 这是热的
Mmm. That's hot.
就像耶稣给我洗了舌头 但就在他要结束之前
It's like Jesus washed my tongue... but right before he finished,
他终于和我爸说 “他够好了”
he finally told my dad, "He's good enough."
非常感谢 约翰尼警官
Thank you so much. Officer Johnny!
祝你过得愉快 盖伊
Have a good one, Guy.
卡布奇诺
Cappuccino.
别有不错的一天... 要有很好的一天 对吧
Don't have a good day... ... have a great day, I guess.
祝你有美好的一天
Okay. Good day to you.
全都趴下
Everybody down on the ground!
没有人想当英雄 这一切很快就会结束的
Nobody try to be a hero. This will all be over soon.
是那个女孩
That's the girl.
我们不会再谈论这个了
We've been over this.
你昨天想跟她说话 但没成功
You tried to talk to her yesterday, it didn't work.
这永远不会成功
It will never work.
她戴着墨镜
She's wearing sunglasses.
我们不招惹戴墨镜的人
We don't mess with the sunglasses people.
也许我该有一副自己的墨镜
Maybe I'll get some sunglasses of my own.
什么 你在说什么 你不能这么做
What? What are you talking about? You can't do that.
哦 我的天 我在做什么?
Oh, my God. What am I doing?
嗨
Hi.
你说什么
What'd you say?
嗨
Hi.
我需要你的墨镜
I'm gonna need your sunglasses.
哦 噢
Ooh. Ow.
我要... 我需要借你的墨镜用一下
I'm just gonna... I'm gonna need your sunglasses for a sec.
你知道你在干什么吗
What the hell do you think you're doing?
回你那边去 伙计
Go back to your side, man.
他只是个非玩家角色 浪费他妈…
He's just an NPC. Waste that mother...
就借一下 好吗
Okay, just need to borrow them for a sec, okay?
-后退 我说 不  -很快就好 真的
- Back off! I said, don't! - Just real quick. Real quick.
停下
Stop!
你是脑子坏了还是怎么了
You broken or somethin'?
我是强盗
I'm the robber!
你是那个乖乖躺着接受的人
You're the guy who lies down and takes it!
拜托 趴下吧
Please, just stay down!
我说了 趴下
I said, stay down!
盖伊 你不能这么做
Guy, you don't do this, man.
这不是你
This isn't you.
你不会这么做的
You don't do this.
也许我就该这么做
Maybe I do.
这个愚蠢的任务到底有什么问题
What is wrong with this... stupid mission?
我告诉你了 杀了他
I told you to smoke his ass.
放开
Let go!
我很快还给你
I'll give them right back.
我说…
I said...
盖伊?
Guy?
他只是在休息
He's just resting.
他的胸口变块状了
In pieces!
那个人死了
That man is dead!
他太困了
He's so sleepy.
我把你的枪放在这里 你醒来就能看到
I'm just gonna put your gun down... right here... for when you wake.
-好吗  -盖伊
- Okay? - Guy.
盖伊 你要去哪里
Guy! Where you goin'?
打扰一下
Excuse me.
你看到这个吗
Do you see this?
周五前把季度报告放在我桌上
Have the quarterly reports on my desk by Friday.
哇呼
Whoo!
哦
Oh!
跑快点
Giddy up!
我感觉焕然一新
I feel brand new.
失败者
Loser.
怎么回事
What is happening?
好多钱
So much money.
嘿 鼠标 看看这个
Hey, Mouser, check this out.
怎么了 键盘
What's up, Keys?
要我看什么
What am I looking at?
这个玩家 他的眼镜被抢 然后被杀了
Okay, so this user, he gets his glasses stolen and then killed.
这家伙被一个非玩家角色干掉了
The guy was smoked by a non-playable character.
非玩家角色? 这不可能
An NPC? That's impossible.
是啊 没错
Yeah, exactly.
没有人可以装备非玩家角色的皮肤
Nobody can equip an NPC skin on their avatar.
对啊 所以你只要踢掉这个垃圾菜鸟 永久封禁他 就完事了
Yeah, so you just boot the trash-ass noob and ban him for life, you're done.
我试过了 但…我追踪不到他
I tried that, but I... I can't trace him.
不管是谁 他们都很厉害
Whoever it is, they're good.
你得把你的工作做得更好 伙计
Hmm. You gotta be better at your job, buddy.
我做得很好啊
I'm pretty good.
我们游戏里见
I'll see you on the inside.
请选择您的皮肤
Select your skin.
键盘 你要用什么皮肤
Hey, Keys, what skin are you going with?
向往常一样 猥琐警察 有大枪 大胡子
The ushe. Dirty stripper cop, big guns, bigger mustache.
小土松鼠 我喜欢
Hmm. Little dirt squirrel. I like it.
我差点不敢问 你想选什么皮肤
Almost scared to ask, but what are you going with?
全身长毛 粉红色的 你应该会很害怕
Uh, full body mustache, hot pink. You should be very afraid.
我害怕极了
I'm terrified.
我们开始吧
Let's do this.
说真的 伙计
Seriously, man.
我只是有话实说 我觉得这兔女郎装有点过了
I'm just being honest, I think the bunny suit is just a little much.
你说什么
Excuse me?
好
Right.
兔子装 行了吧? 是我的错
Rabbit. Okay? My fault.
嘿 40岁的老处男 过来
Hey, 40-year-old virgin! Get over here!
我们走吧
Let's go!
啊哈 卡其裤队长
Uh-huh. Captain Khakis.
-过来这里 来吧 伙计  -走 我们走
- Come here. Come on, bud. - Go, let's go.
-再过来点  -他来了
- Closer. - There he is.
蓝色衬衫的家伙
Blue shirt guy.
蓝色的衬衫?
Blue shirt?
是的
Yes.
你好 警官
Hello, Officer.
兔子
Rabbit.
皮肤不错啊
Nice skin.
谢谢 你真会说话
Thank you. That's sweet.
你怎么弄到的
How'd you get it?
呃 我想主要是遗传吧 我挺幸运的
Well, uh, mostly genetics, I think. I'm pretty lucky.
我有天生水灵灵的皮肤
I have naturally dewy skin.
听好了 露得清[化妆品品牌]
Listen up, Neutrogena.
你不能用这幅样子到处走 规则写很清楚
You know you can't go around looking like that. The rules are clear.
还有另一件事
And another thing.
-你不能黑掉非玩家角色的虚拟替身  -不行 先生
- You can't hack the NPC avatars. - No, sir!
-这搞砸了任务…  -搞砸了
- It screws up the mission load... - Screws it up!
让这游戏看起来很糟糕
...and it makes the game look bad.
-真可怕  -是的
- Horrible! - Yeah.
我大概只明白了你话的5%
I got, like, 5% of that.
脱下皮肤
Lose the skin!
我… 脱下?
I... Lose?
我要怎么脱下我的皮肤
How am I supposed to get rid of my skin?
把它脱掉 伙计
Take it off, man.
脱掉就好 你干嘛呢
Just take it off. What are you doing?
-什么  -说实在的
- What? - Seriously.
-全部脱下 那脸和衣服  -怎么脱
- The whole thing. The face, the outfit. - How?
-全部都脱  -脱下来
- Everything. Ditch it. - Take it off.
如果你不脱 我们就杀了你
If you don't, we're gonna kill you.
-为什么  -我们会一直不停杀你
- Why? - And we're gonna keep killing you.
到底是为什么
Still why?
直到我们查出你的身份... 然后我们会把你永久封禁
Until we do find out who you are... and then we're gonna ban you for life.
好 不 不 好吧 我想照做
Okay. No, no. Okay, I want to comply.
我只是觉得这些威胁的顺序很混乱
I just find the order of those threats very confusing.
-看来有人想吃一枪啊  -开火
- Somebody's about to get shot. - Light him up
不
No.
来吧 蓝衬衫
Come on, Blue Shirt.
哦 没想到会这样 你看到了吗
Oh! Didn't see that one coming. Did you see that one coming?
吓我一跳
Scared me a little bit.
我们来找你了 蓝衬衫
We're coming for you, Blue Shirt!
来收拾你
Coming to get ya.
我们要来收拾你了
We're coming to get ya.
等等 等等
Wait! Wait!
我可以解释
I can explain everything.
我戴了这副眼镜 然后就能看见一些东西了
I found these glasses and then I can see things now.
一些… 不存在的东西
Things that... Whoa, whoa. Things that aren't there.
但又确实存在
Except they are there.
我知道这听起来很疯狂 但这是真的
I know that sounds crazy, but it's true!
你可以逃 蓝衫军 但你躲不了的
You can run, Blue Shirt, but you cannot hide.
来吧 蓝衬衫 你是无法摆脱兔子的
Come on, Blue Shirt. You can't escape the rabbit.
我们是顶级掠食者
We're apex predators.
我们平时所做的就是撕咬 斗殴 和割喉
All we do is bone and brawl and slit throats.
太高了 太高了
Too high! Too high!
你想玩吗 蓝衬衫 那就看好了
Oh, you wanna play, Blue Shirt? Watch this.
我厌倦了这些打闹 键盘
I tire of these games, Keys.
是时候让这娘娘腔见识下上帝模式了
It's time I went god-mode on this beyotch.
好的 来吧
Okay, bring it.
哦 来了 走走走
Oh, it's brung. Go, go, go, go, go.
我非常 非常擅长这个
I'm so, so good at this.
结束了 银行出纳员
Time's up, bank teller!
不
Nope!
我不能死
I can't die!
我是不会死的
I'm never gonna die!
哇
Whoo!
这就是蓝衫哥令人心碎的故事
And that was the heartbreaking story of Blue Shirt Guy.
剧终
The end.
-说不过去啊  -怎么了
- Doesn't make sense. - What?
我刚查了服务器的数据
I just checked the server stats.
我们杀死了蓝衬衫 但是在线玩家的数量并没有改变
We killed Blue Shirt and the number of players online didn't change.
这只是个小故障 伙计
It's just a glitch, man.
-没什么大不了的  -我知道 我知道
- It's not a big deal. - I know, I know.
只是这看起来有些不一样
It just seems like that's something new, you know?
键盘 我知道你在想什么 你别告诉安托万
Keys, I know what you're thinking, okay? You should not talk to Antwan.
我只是觉得开诚布公很重要
I just think it's important to be transparent, okay?
呃 不
Uh-uh. No.
安托万正埋身于续作的发行中 他要么不在乎
Antwan is deep in the sequel launch. He's either not gonna care
要么就很生气 然后就会责怪我们
or he's gonna get pissed and then he's gonna blame us.
我不知道你对现况还有什么没弄明白的
So, I don't know what you haven't figured out about the whole situation.
还有 你不是麻省理工学院的天才
Also, aren't you some kinda MIT genius,
独立游戏设计师吗
indie game designer?
你在这里处理投诉是为什么
What are you doing down here dealing with complaints?
鼠标 这是一个漫长又可悲的故事
That, Mouser, is a long and pathetic story
涉及到失败的梦想 绝望和推挤如山的大学债务
involving failed dreams, desperation, and a mountain of college debt.
你不会想听的
You do not wanna hear about that.
你完全正确的
You're absolutely right.
那个故事听起来可怕又无聊 而且充满了白人特权
That story sounds horrible and boring and full of white privilege.
别告诉安托万
Don't talk to Antwan.
我们做梦也没想过这会发生
We never dreamt this would've happened.
我的意思是 《游戏人生》本质上是一个养鱼游戏
I mean, Life Itself, it's essentially a fishbowl game.
华特 · “键盘” · 麦凯
西雅图独立游戏大会2015
《游戏人生》共同创造者
人们不是在玩游戏 而是在看着它成长
People aren't playing it, they're watching it grow.
严格来说 这是个观察体验
It's a strictly observational experience
观察由电脑生成的角色 互动和发展
where computer generated characters interact and evolve.
我还以为我们能把它送出去就很幸运了
I thought we'd be lucky to give it away.
这就是键盘的魅力所在
That's what's so charming about Keys,
米莉 · 拉斯科
《游戏人生》共同创造者
他对自己的天赋浑然不知
he's clueless about his own genius.
呃不 米莉才是天才
Uh, no, Millie is the genius.
她从零开始制作出了人工智能引擎
Uh, she built the AI engine from the ground up.
说点私人问题吧 你早上起床的动力是什么
So, to get a little personal, what's the thing that gets you up in the morning?
中杯咖啡 加奶油 两块糖
Medium coffee, cream, two sugars.
另一件事是什么来着
What's the other thing?
对了 是想被认可的无尽渴望
Oh, yeah. An insatiable thirst for validation.
-她不是在开玩笑  -我没有
- She's not kidding. - I'm not.
那你呢
How about you?
-代码  -代码?
- Code. - Code?
-代码  -代码 是的
- Code. - Code, yeah.
让我们开始
Here we go.
因为这不仅仅是0和1 还是隐藏的信息
'Cause it's not just zeros and ones, it's hidden messages.
我更喜欢把自己看作一个作者 而不是一个代码编写者
I like to think of myself, actually, as not a code writer, but an author.
我只是用0和1代替文字
I just use zeros and ones instead of words
因为文字会让你失望
'cause words will let you down.
但是0和1不会 0和1酷毙了
But zeros and ones, never. Zeros and ones are as cool as shit.
-他没在开玩笑  -我没有
- He's not kidding. - I'm not.
现在 我得问了
Now, I've gotta ask.
你们之间有很多化学反应
There is a lot of chemistry between the two of you.
-这是不是已经发展成超过…  -没有
- Has this evolved into more than... - No.
-没门 我们完全是柏拉图式的  -不不不 我们是朋友
- No way. No. It's strictly platonic. - No, no, no. We're friends.
-我们就像是最好的朋友  -友谊
- We're like best friends. - Friendship.
现在你们的游戏将由世界上最大的
And now your game is gonna be released by
游戏发行商之一 苏乐美发行
Soonami, one of the biggest publishers in the world.
-这太疯狂了  -就是说啊
- It's crazy, actually. - It is, yeah.
不过 这看起来确实有点不太搭
It does seem a little bit like an unlikely pairing, though.
是啊 我也没完全明白
Yeah, I didn't totally get it either.
-但米莉对这些事有种直觉…  -安托万是个天才
-But Millie's got a real instinct for these things... -Antwan is a genius.
虽然他傲慢又讨人厌 但他真的很擅长他的工作
He's brash and obnoxious, but he's really good at what he does.
这是一个让更多玩家看到我们作品的机会
It's a chance for our work to be seen by a wider audience.
-天啊 那两个人真是又年轻又蠢  -我的天
- God, those two were young and dumb. - Jeez.
现在流行强行闯入这一套吗
So we're breaking and entering now?
为一个冰屎黑洞工作的感觉如何
How does it feel working for a galactic black hole of frozen shit?
你得离开 我不能和你说话
You have to leave. I can't talk to you.
噢 看来你也会觉得羞愧啊
Aw, shame will have that effect.
不 米莉 我是说我不能和你说话
No, Millie. I mean I can't talk to you.
我看不见你 我只是在看这些背景物
I can't even see you. I'm literally focusing on background objects
因为看到你的嘴唇动动一动就会违反我的保密协议
because looking at your lips move violates my NDA
这会让我被解雇
and it could get me fired.
噢 被安托万解雇 那个偷了我们成果的家伙吗
Aw, fired by Antwan, the guy who stole our work?
不 是他买下了游戏 然后弃置了
No, he bought it and then he shelved it.
好吗 你被困在过去 现在你得翻篇了
All right? You're living in the past. You are stuck. You gotta move on.
我怎么可以翻篇
How can I move on?
你怎么可以
How can you?
安托万偷走了我们的人工智能引擎
Antwan swiped our AI engine
用在他那愚蠢的射击游戏中
to use in his dumb shooter.
有吗 米莉 说实话 我不太确定
Did he, Millie? Because honestly, I'm not so sure.
我们的游戏复杂 漂亮 有趣
Our game was complex and beautiful and interesting
而自由城可能很受欢迎 但它太蠢了 蠢得让我想哭
and Free City, it may be popular, but it's so idiotic, it makes me wanna cry.
那就别为他辩护了 帮我揍他一顿
Then stop defending him and help me beat his ass.
-米莉 我…  -拜托 键盘 他偷了我们的成果
- Millie, I'm... - Come on, Keys, he stole from us.
现在他还隐瞒了这件事
And now he's lying about it
这样他就不用给我们应得的荣誉和版税了
so he doesn't have to give us the credit and the royalties that we deserve.
米莉…
Millie...
我发现了一条线索 在一个玩家藏匿处有个视频
I found a clue. It's on a clip in a gamer's stash house.
我只要你把我弄进去
All I need from you is to get me in there.
米莉 我很在乎你…
Millie, I care about you...
但你得离开了
but you need to leave.
今天会不一样的 小金
Today is gonna be different, Goldie.
在看什么
What are we lookin' at?
你是谁
Who are you?
好 好 好
Okay, okay. Okay.
那天我碰见你 你在哼那首很棒的歌
We ran into each other the other day, you were humming that great song.
哦 是啊
Oh, yeah.
我还以为你是非玩家角色 你是怎么找到我的
I thought you were an NPC. How did you find me?
我在谋杀列车外面等着 然后就跟踪了你
I waited outside by the murder train, then I followed you.
狗屎
Shit!
我该和你一块走吗
Should I come with you?
好的
Yes.
我的天 刚刚发生了什么
Holy hell, what just happened?
刚才你差点把我的任务搞砸了
What just happened is you almost blew my mission.
不 我是说 我们是怎么从刚才那地方到这里的?
No, I mean, how did we get from there to wherever this is?
你是说传送枪?
You mean the portal gun?
传送枪? 这听起来贵
Portal gun? That sounds expensive.
哇 你真是个特别的菜鸟
Wow, you are a special kind of noob.
谢谢你 你也一样
Thank you. You too.
转身
Turn around.
好的
Okay.
哦
Oh.
这里是北极吗?
Is this the North Pole?
听着 老兄
Listen, dude.
-我叫盖伊  -盖伊 无所谓
- Guy. - Guy. Whatever.
用着非玩家角色的服装
Props on the NPC outfit,
但我现在忙着想办法偷点东西
but I'm busy trying to figure out how to steal something.
也许我能帮你
Maybe I could help you.
我习惯一个人工作
I work alone.
你还有漂亮的手榴弹
You have beautiful grenades.
此外 如果你想在这里拥有任何影响力
Besides, if you want to have any chance of making an impact here,
你就需要升到更高的等级
you need to have a higher level than that.
-这真难用  -别动
- That's tough. No. - No.
更高的等级?
Higher level?
我的老天爷啊 菜鸟
Good Lord, rook.
看到了吗
See?
-哦  -这是我的等级
- Oh. - That's mine.
而这是你的
And that's yours.
哦… 这是最高的还是最低的?
Oh... What, is one the best or the worst?
简直没有比这更低的了
There is literally nothing lower.
那我要怎么升到更高的等级呢
Well, how do I get to a higher level?
-真的吗 这都不知道?  -真的
- Really? - Really.
-搞到一些东西  -好啊
- You know, get stuff. - Yeah.
-你是在开玩笑吗?  -好的
- Are you kidding me right now? - Okay.
-像经验 枪…  -是的
- Experience, guns... - Yeah.
-把它放下  -嗯
- Put that down. - Uh-huh.
和钱 这是自由城
Money. This is Free City.
你可以抢劫商店 劫车 打路人的脸 总之你会搞明白的
You could rob a store, carjack someone, punch a pedestrian in the face. You'll figure it out.
我从不伤害无辜的人
Oh, I'd never hurt innocent people.
嗯 我得承认这让人耳目一新
Hmm. I've got to admit that is kind of refreshing.
有时我都忘了 这里不是每个人都是反社会的大男孩
Sometimes I forget not everyone you meet on here is a sociopathic man-child.
谢谢你
Thank you.
等等 但这世界并没有那么糟糕 不是吗
Wait. But the world isn't that bad though, is it?
这话说得挺凄凉的
Oh! It's pretty bleak.
如果你见过管这世界的混蛋 你就会同意我了
If you ever met the dick responsible for this world, you'd agree.
我们说的是上帝吗 你见过上帝?
Are we talking about God? You've met God?
他是个混蛋?
And he's a dick?
他叫安托万 没错 他绝对是个巨魔
His name's Antwan, and yes, he's an absolute troll.
巨魔存在吗
Trolls exist?
听着 我不知道有没有人会这么做
Look, I don't know if anybody does it,
但你可以通过做个好人来增加经验值
but you could rack experience points up by being a good guy.
-就像个英雄  -哦 放轻松 猛虎
- Like a hero. - Ooh. Easy, tiger.
如果你不想对人开枪 那你可以偷他们的枪
If you don't wanna shoot people, you could steal their guns.
所有这些狗屎都能让你的等级提高
All that shit makes your level go up.
去做个好人
Go be the good guy.
好吧 不 我要做个很好的人
Okay. No, I'm gonna be the great guy.
噢 噢
Ooh! Ooh.
好吧 去享受你不渝的童贞吧
Okay, well, enjoy your lifetime supply of virginity.
你可以走了
Off you go.
好吧 等等 我要怎么知道我我的等级够不够高?
Okay. Wait! How will I know that I've leveled up enough?
-超过100级 然后我们再谈  -哇
- Uh, get over 100, then we'll talk. - Whoa.
-回头见  -那可比1级高多了
- Bye now. - That's so much more than one.
-至少高了99级…  -回头见
- It's like 99 more... - Bye now.
好吧
Okay.
嗨
Hi.
谢谢你 盖伊
Thanks, Guy.
早安 小金
Good morning, Goldie.
早他妈的安 小金
Good fucking morning, Goldie.
我要和你们说三个字 蓝衫哥
I have three words for you. Blue Shirt Guy.
GMA 流行新闻
自由城奇人爆红
蓝衫哥
蓝衫哥 正通过扮演英雄以创纪录的速度升级
BSG is leveling up and at a record pace by playing the hero.
全世界的人都在问 “这家伙到底是谁?”
It's got people all over the world asking, "Just who is this guy?"
我不知道这家伙是谁 但他的技术比所有玩家都厉害
I don't know who this guy is, but he's out-skilling all these players.
这就是他 干掉了诸神黄昏家族102级的牛肉烤箱
And here he is, taking out Beefoven, a level 102 from Clan Ragnarok.
太胡扯了 这家伙是谁
This is bullshit. Who is this guy?
我不知道 但他很厉害
I don't know, but he's good.
是啊 他很厉害 他看起来像个非玩家角色 但他四处奔走
Yeah, he's good. He looks like an NPC but he's running around,
通过做个该死的好人来疯狂升级
leveling up crazy fast by being the freaking good guy.
电子游戏《自由城》中这个富有色彩的角色
"This colorful character in the video game Free City
因为好人行径而引发关注
has been turning heads by being the good guy."
-派珀  -蓝衫哥是谁
- Piper. - Who is Blue Shirt Guy?
你问得太好了
You're absolutely right.
蓝衫哥 他或她到底是谁
Blue Shirt Guy. Who is he or she indeed?
哇呼
Whoo-hoo!
有一种风靡全球的潮流俘获了孩子们的心 蓝衫哥
There's a worldwide craze that has captured kids' hearts-- Blue Shirt Guy!
你好 日向
Hello, Hinata.
你的衣服真棒
You have a great outfit.
别有不错的一天 要有很好的一天
Don't have a good day, Have a GREAT day!
太棒了
Crazy awesome!!!
好了 好了 看看是谁来上班了
Well, well, well. Look who decided to come to work today, huh?
你去哪里了 我担心死你了…
Look, where have you been? I've been worried sick about you...
这件衬衫是怎么回事
What is this shirt?
你的衣领呢 其余的纽扣呢
Where's your collar at? Where's the rest of the buttons?
衬衫也没塞进裤子里 你看起来很邋遢
And it's not tucked in. You look sloppy.
事实上 你看起来糟透了 你还练肌肉了吗
Matter of fact, you look horrible. Did you pick up some muscles, too?
还是有人帮你充气[鼓动你]?
Or is somebody outside pumping you up?
很抱歉最近我都没陪你 巴迪
I'm sorry that I haven't been around, Bud.
我在搞清楚一些事情
I've been figuring some stuff out.
你说"搞清楚"是什么意思 没什么好搞清楚的
Whatcha mean, "figure stuff out"? It is nothing to figure out.
你睡觉 然后醒来 喝杯咖啡 再去上班
Okay? You go to bed, you wake up, you get some coffee, then you come to work.
然后你明天再重复同样的事情
And then you repeat the same thing tomorrow.
-那个女孩  -我的天啊
- The girl. - Oh, my God.
我和她谈过了 我和她谈过了
I talked to her. I talked to her.
-戴墨镜的那个?  -墨镜 对
- The one with the sunglasses? - The sunglasses, yes!
我和一个戴墨镜的人谈过 现在我也是他们的一员了
I talked to one of the sunglass people and now I'm one of the sunglass people.
我
Me.
全部人都到地上
Everybody down on the ground!
你好性感
You're so hot.
如果我告诉你 你能变得更好呢
What if I could tell you that you could be more?
你的生活可以变得更充实
Your life could be fuller.
你可以自己做决定 自己做选择
That you're free to make your own decisions. Your own choices.
哟 蠢蛋
Yo, dumbass.
我们在忙
We are in the middle of something.
-那是我的枪  -安静
-Uh... That's my gun. - Quiet time.
这玩意儿改变了我的生活 也能改变你的
These puppies changed my life. And they're gonna change yours, too.
得了吧 你知道我们不戴墨镜的
Come on now, you know we don't wear sunglasses.
我们现在会了
We do now.
现在是我的了
Mine now.
你在跟我开玩笑吧
Are you kidding me?
-戴上  -不要
- Put 'em on. - No.
生活不止有我们经历的那些 好吗
Life doesn't have to be something that just happens to us. All right?
戴上眼镜 你就知道了
Just put the glasses on and you're gonna see.
你会看到的
You're gonna see.
来吧
Come on.
我不能
I can't, okay?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我要留着这个 混蛋
I'm keeping these, asshole mouth.
现在给我离开这里 去做个好人
Now get out of here. Go be nicer.
走开 走 走 走
Beat it. Go, go, go.
不要用走 用跑的
Don't walk, run.
而你… 啊
And you... Ugh.
抱歉
Sorry.
你能找到比那家伙更好的
Um, you could do so much better than that guy.
你可以和一个好男人在一起
You could be with, like, a good guy.
也许我不需要和任何男人在一起
Or maybe I don't have to be with any guy.
是吧? 没错 大多数男人都很糟糕
Right? Exactly. Most of them are awful.
-他们确实如此  -糟透了
- They really are. - Terrible.
你想怎么做就怎么做
Yeah, do whatever you wanna do.
你是我最好的朋友 巴迪
You're my best friend, Buddy.
你不用害怕
And you don't have to be scared.
如果你改变主意了 我就在附近
If you change your mind, I'll be around.
键盘 我们的蓝衫哥到处都是
Yo, Keys, our Blue Shirt Guy is everywhere.
我知道
I know.
这家伙到底是谁
Who is this guy?
我想尽快和你谈谈
拜托
我们的证据就在那个藏匿处
我一个人做不到 我试过了
我来了
I'm here.
我真的很感激 键盘
I really appreciate this, Keys.
好吧 先说清楚 我只是负责把门打开
Okay. Just to be clear, all I'm doing right now is opening the door.
如果这段视频真的能证明安托万
If this clip really does prove that Antwan
非法重复使用我们的代码 那就去找出来然后离开
reused our code illegally, go find it and get out.
那玩家在市中心做着珠宝店任务
Player's doing the jewelry store mission in midtown.
你有5分钟的时间
That gives you 5 minutes.
去吧
And go.
键盘 你他妈真是个天才
Keys, you're a goddamn genius.
真的吗
Really?
我现在正坐在马桶上 偷用户密码
I'm sitting on the toilet right now, stealing user codes,
所以我完全不觉得自己是
so I don't exactly feel like one.
哦 你从来都不觉得自己是
Oh, you never have.
还好我自己知道得更多
Good thing I know better.
你要找的视频应该就在你左边的墙上
All right. The clip you're looking for should be on the wall to your left.
-谢谢你的帮助  -没问题
- Thanks for the assist. - You got it.
我希望那里有你想要的证据
I hope it has the proof you're looking for.
键盘 我需要你的帮助
Keys! I need your help!
他在那地方设了陷阱 还设了出生点
He's got that place booby-trapped with spawn points.
米莉 我帮不了你
Millie, I can't help you.
蓝衫男?
Blue Shirt Guy?
这是辆亨利 酷吗 我觉得真的很酷
It's a Henley. Was that cool? It felt really cool.
你看起来真漂亮 哇 这房子也很漂亮
You look really pretty. Wow, this house is so nice.
你在这里做什么
What are you doing here?
我本来是想偷一段视频 但现在我们要做的是保住性命
I was trying to steal a video clip, now we're trying not to die.
你在跟谁说话
Who are you talking to?
就是那个披着非玩家角色皮肤的玩家
You know, that player in the NPC skin.
米莉 那房子里没有其他玩家
Millie, there are no other players in that house.
我的手都打疼了
That actually hurt my hand.
趴下
Get down!
我很抱歉 哦 天啊
I'm sorry! Oh, God!
我们干的很棒
We're doing great.
哇
Wow!
我们该走了
We should definitely go!
哦 该死的
Oh, shit!
-你口袋里是把格洛克手枪吗  -不是
- Is that a Glock in your pocket? - No.
-什么  -是两把格洛克手枪
- What? - It's two Glocks.
哦
Oh!
我不觉得这东西能飞起来
I don't suppose this thing can fly.
不能
No.
跳
Jump.
哇
Wow!
Whoa!
哦 该死
Oh, shit.
早安 小绵羊们
Good morning, sheeple!
哦 你被解雇了
Oh, you are fired.
有些人担心血腥僵尸会让零售商不给游戏上架
There is some concern with the bloody zombies, retailers won't carry the game.
那就砍掉 不用了 不能让这种事发生 下一个
Cut it. It's out. Never even happened. Next.
你的律师来电 他们需要你的证词
It's your lawyers. They need to get your deposition...
说话 我们说的是哪起诉讼?
Speak. Which lawsuit are we talking about?
米莉 米莉·拉斯科? 没问题的
Millie, Millie Rusk? No sweat.
这事连法庭都进不了...
That will never see the inside of a courtroom...
因为她没有证据 而她的前搭档在为我工作
because she's got no proof and her ex-partner works for me.
我们是最棒的
We're golden.
安托万 嘿 你看起来很好
Antwan, hey. You look great.
我以为你还在火人祭呢
Uh, I thought you were still at Burning Man.
我看起来像还在火人祭吗
Oh, does it look like I'm still at Burning Man?
-你 你 你…  -闭上你的臭嘴 听我说
You, you, you... No. So, shut your stupid, bearded face and listen.
你听说游戏里有个看起来像非玩家角色的混蛋了吗
You heard about the asshole running around in the game who looks like an NPC?
是的 是的 我们叫他蓝衫哥 我们会除掉他的
Yeah, yeah. We call him Blue Shirt Guy. But we're gonna get rid of him.
不要除掉他 人们都喜欢他 社交媒体上到处都是他
Don't get rid of him. People like him. It's all over social media. No.
知道我要做什么吗 我要把这皮肤用在自由城2
In fact, know what I'm gonna do? I'm gonna use the skin in Free City 2.
哦 艺术呆子们 我们要升级一下蓝衫 好吗
Oh, art nerds! We're gonna make some upgrades to Blue Shirt, all right?
加点类固醇 让他变成杀手之类的
'Roid him out. Make him a hitman or something.
安托万 我们移植自由城1皮肤的进度已经落后了
Antwan, we're already way behind porting over the skins from Free City 1.
皮肤? 不用担心这个
Skins? Don't even worry about that.
那些在《自由城2》里用不了
They won't be usable in Free City 2.
安托万 你告诉粉丝们…《自由城2》可以向下兼容的
Antwan, you told the fans... Free City 2 is backwards compatible.
广告里都有 你说续作里会有同样的角色
It was in the commercial. You said there'd be the same characters in the sequel.
事情是这样的 我那些话是骗人的
Well, here's the thing. When I said that, I was lying.
听着 安托万 这个游戏的问题越来越多了
Listen, Antwan, the game is already buggier than ever.
我收到的用户投诉有一英里高
I got a stack of user complaints, like a mile high.
我知道这很糟糕
Look, I know it sucks.
但这知识产权的认可度非常高 所以不用担心
But the IP recognition is rock hard. Okay? So don't even worry about it.
我只是说说而已 我们可以做一款原创游戏
I'm just saying, we could make an original game.
什么
What?
做原创游戏? 既然我可以续作 那我为什么要做原创
Make an original? Why would I do that when I could make a sequel?
续作
A sequel.
这样我们就能做得更好?
So we can make it better?
系列和续集才是人们想要的
IPs and sequels, that is the thing that people want.
-我问你个问题  -好的
- Let me ask you a question. - Okay.
你喜欢肯德基炸鸡 对吧
You love Kentucky Fried Chicken, right?
-嗯  -不
- Mmm-hmm. - No.
如果你爱吃肯德基炸鸡 而我是做肯德基炸鸡的
If you love Kentucky Fried Chicken, and I make Kentucky Fried Chicken,
然后我知道你爱吃肯德基炸鸡 那我为什么要开一家
and I know that you love Kentucky Fried Chicken, why would I make another restaurant
叫"阿尔伯克水煮火鸡"的餐厅呢
called,uh, I don't know, "Albuquerque Boiled Turkey"?
-对吗 这没意义啊啊 哥们  -嗯 毫无意义
- Okay? Makes no sense, homie. - Mmm-hmm. No sense.
我该给你什么? 是续作 肯德基炸鸡 第二部
What am I gonna give you? A sequel. Kentucky Fried Chicken-Chicken, Part Two.
让他见鬼去吧
Uh, yum. Drop the deuce on him.
来吧 过来 来这里
Come on. Come here. Come here.
我不想让你这发质好的脑袋感到压力
I don't want you to stress that glorious shampoo commercial head of yours about it.
《自由城2》会很举目吉欧斯的
Free City 2 is gonna be jumunjious.
这不是一个词
That's not a word.
你确定你不想去编程部吗
You sure you don't wanna bump up to programming?
我知道你有那个能力
I know you got the brains for it.
不了 谢谢 我在这很好
No thanks. I'm good right where I am.
你喜欢就好 对高位恐惧 我也不知道该说什么
Love it. Fear of flying. Can't say I can relate.
只要不用加你薪水 我都没关系
But all good with me if I don't have to pay you more.
安托万走了
Antwan out.
这家伙到底是谁
Who is this guy?
哇
Wow!
我听取了你的建议
I took your advice.
我升级了
I leveled up.
厉害嘛
Impressive.
你为什么要这么做
Why are you doing all of this?
我觉得自己被 困住了
You know, I guess I felt... trapped.
被生活困住
You know, in my life.
-感觉就像…  -卡住了
-I just felt so... -Stuck.
是的 然后我遇见了你
Yeah. And then I saw you.
遇见了你
Then I saw you.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是盖伊
I'm Guy.
不 你到底是谁
No, who are you really?
盖伊啊
Still Guy.
所有这些东西 还有升级得这么快
All of this, leveling up so fast.
向世界竖起中指
Giving this whole world the finger.
你是怎么做到的
How are you pulling this off?
我从来没对人竖起过中指
I've never given anyone any of my fingers.
你在苏乐美工作 对吧
You work at Soonami, don't you?
-不是  -你有内线
- No. - You've got an inside track.
-我在银行工作  -好吧 银行
- I work at the bank. - Right. The bank.
所以 你只是个刚好在银行工作的超级黑客
So, you're just this incredible hacker who happens to work at the bank.
是的 我在银行工作
Yes, I work at the bank.
你的皮肤从哪儿来的
Where did you get that skin?
它一直都在我身上
It's always sort of been there.
为什么人们都问我这个问题
Why do people keep asking me that question?
我不知道 为什么呢
I don't know, why do they?
不 不 不这样做 我… 现在什么事情在发生
No, no. Not doing that. I... What's happening right now?
我不知道 但我不信
I don't know, but I don't buy it.
不
No.
-好 随它吧  -好 好的
- Okay, fine. I'll forget it. - Fine. Good.
-我不管了  -好的
- I'll let it go. - Yes.
太好了
Great.
我想 大家都有自己的秘密
We all have our secrets, I guess.
是的 没错
Yes, we do.
嘿
Hey.
你喜欢冰淇淋吗
Do you like ice cream?
真不敢相信我从没来过这里
I can't believe I've never been here.
这是一个秘密
Well, it's sort of a secret.
这就是为什么我和我朋友巴迪总是来这里 这里既安静又安全
That's why me and my buddy, Buddy, always come here. It's quiet and safe.
有道理
Yeah, it makes sense.
这里没有任务
No missions here.
你得尝尝这个 你会觉得我疯了
Oh, you gotta try this. You're gonna think I'm crazy.
这是我世界上最喜欢的口味
This is my favorite flavor in the whole world.
请给我们两粉普通的
We'll take two of the usual, please.
收到 盖伊
You got it, Guy.
这是泡泡糖口味
It's bubble gum flavor.
你觉得我疯了 对吗
You think I'm crazy, don't you?
盖伊… 滚出我的脑子 我超喜欢泡泡糖冰淇淋的
Guy... Get out of my brain hole! I love bubble gum ice cream.
不 你才不 你是在取笑我吗
No, you don't. Are you making fun of me right now?
不 没有其他人喜欢泡泡糖冰淇淋
No! Nobody likes bubble gum ice cream.
不 我喜欢
No, I do.
我有段感情因为泡泡糖冰淇淋而结束
I had a relationship end over bubble gum ice cream.
-不是 来  -好
- No way. Here. - Yeah.
-干杯  -干杯
- Cheers. - Cheers.
嗯
Mmm.
很美味对吧
How good is that?
你能尝出味道?
You can taste it?
味道? 就像我的舌头上刚生了个婴儿
Taste it? It's like my tongue had a baby with a sunrise.
-嗯?  -嗯
- Mmm-hmm? - Mmm.
咖啡曾经是我最喜欢的食物
Coffee used to be my favorite food,
但和这个相比 它就像折磨
but compared to this, it tastes like liquid suffering.
怎么了
What?
没什么 你很有趣
Nothing. You're funny.
-是吗  -是的
- I am? - Yeah.
离奇的幽默
Weird funny.
但对我很受落
But that's kind of my speed.
离奇的幽默 这对我也很受落
Weird funny, that's totally my speed, too.
-太棒了  -对了 我知道一个笑话
- Great. - Yeah. I know a joke.
一个离奇有趣的笑话 你想听吗?
A weird funny joke. You wanna hear it?
-请  -好的
- Please. - Okay.
一个同性恋者和一个坐轮椅的人试图谋杀一个小孩…
A homosexual and a man in a wheelchair are trying to murder a very small child...
-跛子对同性恋说…  -哇 停停
- The cripple says to the homosexual... - Whoa. Stop, stop.
停 你从哪儿听来的
Stop! Where did you hear that?
在一场抢劫 枪手把这段话告诉了司机
A robbery. The gunman told it to the driver
司机觉得很搞笑 所以我就把这记下来告诉了所有人
who thought it was hilarious, so I memorized it and told everyone.
给你一个忠告
Word of advice?
别从自由城的巨魔那里抄来笑话
Don't crib your jokes from the trolls of Free City.
巨魔?
Trolls?
那个是秋千吗
Is that a swing set?
天啊…
Holy...
好吧 这太奇怪了
Okay, this is too weird.
复古玛丽亚 泡泡糖冰淇淋 现在是秋千?
Vintage Mariah, bubble gum ice cream, and now swings?
-这太奇怪了  -我也这么觉得
- This is too weird. - I thought the same thing, too.
我也这么觉得
I thought the same thing.
我小时候 很喜欢玩秋千
When I was younger, I was obsessed with swings.
生长在我的家庭是… 你不会想听的
Growing up in my family, it was... You don't wanna hear this. No.
我什么都想听
Oh, I wanna hear everything.
哦
Oh.
生在我家庭里 很难有出息
Growing up in my family, it wasn't good enough to be great.
必须赢的那种压力是经常有的
You had to win, and that pressure, you know, it was just constant.
但当我在后院里荡那小秋千的时候…
But when I was in the backyard on that little swing...
你知道吗 那一刻 在起落之间的那一刹那
You know that moment, that split second between rising and falling,
整个人完全失重时 会感觉到自由
when you're totally weightless, it feels like you're free.
恋爱了
In love.
自由 你说的
Free. What you said. Yeah.
我真的很想吻你 这很奇怪吗
I really wanna kiss you. Is that weird?
你想吻我吗
You want to kiss me?
我想狠狠地吻你
I wanna kiss you so badly.
你想狠狠地吻我?
You want to kiss me badly?
-不  -不是吗
- No! - No?
不不不 我是想好好地吻你
No, no, no, no, no. I wanna kiss you well.
我是个白痴 所以我有时说话会像个白痴一样
I mean, I'm an idiot, so I say things like an idiot sometimes.
不 你不是 你才不是
No, you're not. You're not.
我是说 如果你知道怎么做 那就做吧
I mean, um, uh, if you know how to, go for it.
我知道怎么做
I know how.
好吧
Okay.
来了
Here it goes.
那味道可比冰淇淋好多了
That was so much better than ice cream.
哇
Whoa!
我想有人在敲门
I think someone's at the door.
我也有同感
I'll say.
这真是太棒了
Well, this was great.
-是啊  -我们之后再见面吧 好吗
- Yeah, it was. - Let's meet up again sometime soon. Yeah?
好 一定
Yes. Definitely.
也许在现实世界里界面
Maybe in the real world.
什么
What?
好啊 好啊
Yeah. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
-好的 再见  -好的
- Okay. Bye. - Okay.
再见 鸡尾酒女孩
Bye, Molotov.
嘿… 我的真名是米莉
Hey... my real name is Millie.
我的真名还是盖伊
My real name continues to be Guy.
米莉 开门 米莉 是我键盘 开门 快点
Millie, open up! Millie, it's me, it's Keys! Open up! Come on!
米莉 是我 开门
Millie! It's me, open up!
-什么事  -你是对的
- What? - You were right.
-你是对的  -噢 请进
- You were right. - Oh, come on in.
你是对的 我们的代码就在自由城 而且米莉 代码很管用
You were right. Our code, it is in Free City and, Millie, it works.
是啊 我知道 但我们没有证据
Yeah, I know. But we don't have proof.
先把这事忘了吧
Just forget about that for one second.
我想说 我们的游戏《游戏人生》中
I'm saying that our game, Life Itself,
角色的成长和改变让人觉得很真实…
where characters would grow and change and feel real...
-是啊?  -成功了
- Yeah? - ...worked.
-键盘  -人工智能成功了
- Keys. - The AI worked.
这就是为什么自由城这么逼真 人们这么喜爱它
It's the reason why Free City is so realistic and people love it so much.
而且当然它们看起来会不一样了
And of course it doesn't look the same.
没有瀑布 没有蝴蝶和独角兽
There's no waterfalls, there's no butterflies and unicorns,
所有的角色都有不同的皮肤 他们当然会改掉
all the characters have different skins. Of course they do.
但游戏的底层代码是一样的 那是我们的代码
But the underlying code in the game is the same. Our code.
至于盖伊 他已经进化得远远超出了我们的想象
And Guy, I mean, he has evolved way further than we thought was even possible.
等等 你是说那个披着非玩家角色皮肤的黑客吗
Wait, are you talking about the hacker in the NPC skin?
米莉 我是说那个蓝衫哥…
Millie, I'm talking about the fact that Blue Shirt Guy... Yeah?
其实不是玩家
...is not a player.
他是个自以为活着的算法
He is an algorithm who thinks he's alive.
从技术上来讲 他还活着
I mean, hell, technically, he is alive.
他是第一个真正的人工智能
He is the first real artificial intelligence.
-不 不  -我知道
- No! No. - I know.
-不不不  -是的 是的
- No, no, no. - Yeah, yeah.
-盖伊? 我的盖伊?  -盖伊
- Guy? My Guy? - Guy.
-一个…  -你的盖伊?
- One who has been... - Your Guy?
-天啊…  -这是件好事
- Holy... - This is a good thing.
不 这真的很糟糕
No, it's really bad.
米莉 他的代码比原先的要大几千倍
Millie, his code, it's thousands of times the size it should be.
我们成功了 米尔斯
We did it, Mills.
我们做到了 我们想要创造的一切 都成真了
We did it. Everything that we wanted to create, it actually happened.
你知道非玩家角色也有私人生活吗
Okay? Did you know that the NPCs have private lives?
其中一位咖啡师通过反复试验学会了如何制作卡布奇诺
One of the baristas learned how to make a cappuccino through trial and error.
我的意思是 这真的很难 我都做不到
I mean, that's really difficult. I can't even do that.
我连自己早上喝的燕麦奶都泡不出泡沫
I can't even froth my own oat milk in the morning.
游戏中肉弹这角色写了一本回忆录
And the Bombshell character in the game wrote a memoir
控诉性别歧视 父权制…
that's a searing indictment of gender roles, the patriarchy...
虽然有点唠叨 但总体来说还是不错的
It's a little preachy in parts, but overall, it's pretty good.
米莉 我们得庆祝一下
Millie, we have to celebrate!
-不 这不可能  -你在说什么?
- No, this can't be happening. - What are you talking about?
-这就是我们努力的目标  -不 我让他吻了我
- This is what we've been working for! - No, I let him kiss me!
所以 是的
So, yeah.
抱歉 等等 你让谁吻你了?
I'm sorry, wait, you let who kiss you?
盖伊
Guy.
盖伊?
Guy?
这是我有生以来第一次吻一个正常的男人
The first time I kiss a non-toxic guy in like forever
当然 他甚至不是个真人
and of course he's not even real!
呃 游戏里没有亲吻的按键啊
Uh, there's not a button for that.
他找到那按键了
Oh, he found the button.
-好的  -是的
- Okay. - Yeah.
-我很困惑  -为什么会这么热
- I am... I'm so confused. - Why is it so hot?
而且非常好奇
And surprisingly curious.
你让一个人工智能的
You let an artificially intelligent
-电子游戏角色吻你?  -你能别这么说了吗?
- video game character kiss you? - Oh, okay, can you just stop saying it like that?
-然后你认为那会是…  -因为你得见见他 键盘
-And then you thought that would be... -Because you have got to meet him, Keys.
他很风趣 很善良 还很帅
He's funny, and he's sweet, and he's so handsome.
天啊 我终于说出来了
Oh, my God, now I'm saying it out loud.
还有 米莉 仔细想想 他才四岁
Also, Millie, food for thought, he's like four.
-真的吗? 你要说这些吗  -真的
- Really? You're gonna do that? - Really.
你说得真吓人
Wow, you just made that really creepy.
米莉 把这些都放在一边 不管奇不奇怪
Millie, put all that aside. Weird or not,
如果人们知道了这事 你可能会获得诺贝尔奖 哦,天啊
when people find out about this, you could win a Nobel Prize. Oh, God.
什么
What?
天啊 如果他们看到这个…
Oh, my God, if they see this...
-什么 怎么了  -哦
- What? What is it? - Oh!
安托万啊 还会有什么
Antwan. What else?
他在撒谎 他盗用了我们的代码
He's lying. He lied about using our code,
还撒谎说游戏是向下兼容的
he's been lying about the game being backwards compatible.
我觉得他在《自由城1》也撒了谎
I think he's lying about Free City 1.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
看 这上面没有任务 没有地点…
Look. You see? There's not one mission, not one location...
连一个《自由城1》的角色都没有
I mean, there's not even a single character from Free City 1 on here.
《自由城2》不是个更新…
Free City 2 is not an update...
-它是替代品  -没错
- It's a replacement. - Exactly.
所以当《自由城2》在周一发行时…
So when Free City 2 launches on Monday...
蓝衫哥还有我们代码相关的所有证据 都会被删除
Blue Shirt Guy, all proof of our code, everything will be deleted.
他不能那样做
He can't do that.
我是说 我们面对的是人工生命 这太疯狂了
I mean, this is artificial life we're dealing with. I mean, that's insane.
我们完蛋了
We're screwed.
也许不会
Maybe not.
如果我们能在游戏中找到我们的源代码 就能证明
If we can find our original build in the game, it'll prove that
安托万在没有适当授权的情况下使用了我们的代码
Antwan used our code without properly licensing it.
我们要在《自由城2》发行前找到它
And we just have to find it before Free City 2 launches.
我们有48小时
We have 48 hours.
我找过了 键盘 你知道的
I've looked, Keys. You know I have.
我知道你找过了
I know you have.
但现在我们都知道蓝衫哥的事了 也许他能帮上忙?
But now that we both know about Blue Shirt Guy, maybe he can help?
那就意味着我得告诉他
That would mean I'd have to tell him.
米莉 续作发行后他就不存在了
Millie, he's not gonna exist once the sequel launches.
他的整个世界都会毁灭
His whole world's about to end.
你不觉得他会想要一个机会来挽救吗
Don't you think he'd want a chance to save it?
-给你  -谢谢
- Here you go. - Thank you.
-没问题  -盖伊?
- You got it. - Guy?
嘿 嗨
Hey! Hi!
盖伊 我们得谈谈
Guy, we need to talk.
你的声音怎么了 你的澳大利亚口音呢
What's going on with your voice? Where's your Australian accent?
是英国口音
British.
我觉得我能分辨出澳大利亚口音
I think I know an Australian accent when I see one.
我把变声器关掉了
I turned off the accent filter.
这就是我
This is me.
好
Good.
听着 我有件很重要的事要告诉你
Look, I have to tell you something really important.
你结婚了吗
Are you married?
不
No.
哦 天啊
Oh, God.
那会是史上最糟糕的事情
That would have been like the worst thing ever.
也许还不是最糟糕的
Maybe not the worst thing.
嗯
Huh.
我得给你看点东西
I have to show you something.
好吧
Okay.
哇
Wow!
我一直很好奇这里面有什么
I always wondered what was in here.
收看《杀戮镜头》了解今日自由城每一个血腥
Tune in to the Kill Cam for more of today's highlights of every bloody,
弹痕遍布的角落 和更多精彩片段
bullet-ridden corner of Free City.
有人看见我的猫吗?
Has anyone seen my cat?
哈 这是菲利斯 她总是搞丢她的猫
Hey, that's Phyllis. She's always losing her cats.
还有乔 他是我朋友 我认识他
And there's Joe! He's my friend, I know that guy.
我没搞清楚...这是什么地方?
I don't get it. What is this place?
一言难尽 但这整座城市就是个游戏
There is no easy way to say this, but this city is a game.
一言难尽 我也知道是个游戏
There's no easy way to say this, I know it's a game.
是你教我怎么玩的 噗噗
You taught me how to play it. Boop-boop.
是的 是我教的
Yes, you're right, I did.
但这不仅仅"像"个游戏 本来就是个游戏
But it's not just that it's like a game. It is a game.
一个电子游戏 就是这样
It's a video game. And that's all it is.
所以这是个游戏世界?
So the entire world is a game?
是的
Yes.
我们只是游戏中的玩家?
And we're all just players in the game?
不完全是
Not exactly.
我是玩家
I'm a player.
所有的人都是玩家 存在于现实世界中
All these people here are players. We live in the real world.
但是你只存在于这里
But you only exist here.
这就是你永远无法离开自由城的原因
It's why you can never leave Free City.
你就是大家说的非玩家角色
You're what we call an NPC.
非玩家角色
NPC.
他们叫我警察和大肌肌兔 非玩家角色又是什么?
The policeman and the muscular bunny rabbit, they called me that. What is an NPC?
让我们来…  -看那边
- Let's take... - Just watch.
所有人趴下!
Everybody get down on the ground!
别逞英雄
Nobody try to be a hero.
就能赶快结束这一切
This will all be over soon.
我没听懂
I don't understand.
你是 非玩家角色
You're a non-player character.
非…  -一个背景人物
- Non... - A background person.
这些背景人物能营造真实感
Someone designed to make the game more fun for real people.
等等 等一下 停一下
Wait, hold on a second. Just stop for a second.
我确认一下自己理解的对不对
I wanna make sure I'm getting this straight.
我只是想确认
I just wanna fully understand here.
我是假人?
So, I'm fake?
整个世界都是假的?我甚至不是主角 只是个在背景运作的白痴?
The entire world is fake? I'm not even a main character, I'm just this idiot who's in the background?
米莉 你为什么要说这种话? 我明明就很爱你啊
Millie, why are you even saying this? I love you.
你有这些想法也是程式码设定好的
You only think that because it's in your programming.
盖伊 你得听我说
Guy, I need you to listen to me.
游戏只剩两天就要下线了 永远停止运作
In two days, the game is gonna shut down. For good.
这款续作一旦发表 整个城市 包括你在内
When this sequel launches, this whole city, you,
所有非真实的玩家都会永远消失 你得听我说
all the people in it who aren't players, they'll be gone forever. You need to listen.
我一生总觉得缺少些什么
My whole life, I felt like there had to be something more.
直到我看见了你
And then I saw you.
我才知道我是对的 我是对的!
And I knew I was right. I was right!
有一瞬间 我是那么的惊喜
And for a second, I felt amazing.
我知道 -然而你并不知道
I know. - Except you don't know.
因为我们不是一个世界的人
Because we're not the same.
你不是这么说的吗?你说
Isn't that what you said? You said that.
我们不是一个世界的人
We're not the same.
你是真实的
You're real.
而我是什么? 我是什么?
And I'm what? I'm what?
你不是真的
You're not.
我也许不是真实的
Well, I may not be real,
但至少有那么一瞬间我... 感觉到活着
but for a second there... I felt pretty alive.
全...都是谎言!
It's all a lie!
周五前把季度报告交到我桌上
Have the quarterly reports on my desk by Friday.
"季度报告" 天哪!真是精准的商业术语
Quarterly reports. My, what specific business lingo.
哇 生活在都市里是全世界最棒的事
Wow. Life in the big city. Ain't nothing like it.
直到它粉碎你的灵魂
Until it crushes your soul.
有人看见我的猫吗?有人看见我的…
Has anyone seen my cat? Has anyone seen my...
你的猫?没有 菲利斯 从没见过
Your cats? No, Phyllis, I haven't seen them.
但我有个大胆的想法...关上你该死的门
But here's a revolutionary idea... close your goddamn door.
它们不是啦啦队 一只接一只叠起来把锁打开
It's not like they're climbing on top of one another, forming a little kitty tower, and then jimmying the locks.
它们没有手指头 菲利斯
They don't have thumbs, Phyllis.
没有手指头!!
No thumbs!
你还不明白吗?这里没人明白吗?
Don't you get it? Don't any of you get it?
这一切都不重要!全是假的!我们根本不重要
None of this matters! None of it! It's fake! We don't matter!
那栋楼...假的 这条街...假的!
That building, that's fake! This street... It's fake!
那辆车……
That car...
约翰尼警官
Officer Johnny!
祝你愉快 盖伊
Have a good one, Guy.
哦 嗨 呃…进来吧
Oh, hey, uh... Come in.
给你
Here you go.
谢谢你
Thank you.
兄弟 如果你突然发现自己不是真实的，你会怎么办?
Buddy, what would you do if you found out that you weren't real?
你在讲什么?
What do you mean?
就假装一下 如果
Pretend with me.
好吧 那…我能假装自己是鬼吗?
Okay, so... Can I pretend I'm a ghost?
请便
Sure.
那我看起来会像现在这样吗?还是像死掉之后?
Oh. Do I look like how I look like now? Or whenever I die?
我是不是穿了丧服?
Like, do I have a funeral outfit on?
是那种葬礼…  -不重要
- This is kind of funeral... - Doesn't matter.
既然这是制服...毕竟我也打了领带
...but even though it's a work uniform, 'cause I got a tie on.
我们进入下一阶段 好吗?
Let's move on from the concept, okay?
明白了
Got it.
我不是鬼 满失望的 但我能理解 -恩
I'm not a ghost. I'm very disappointed, but I get it. - Yeah.
我就是我啊 活生生的我 正在帮助朋友
I'm me, who I am right now, and I'm just trying to help a friend.
我说 好吧 "如果"我不是真实的呢?
I say, okay, so what if I'm not real?
拍谢.."又怎样?"
I'm sorry. "So what?"
没错 那又怎样?
Yeah. So what?
但如果你不是真实存在 不就意味着你做什么都不重要了?
But if you're not real, doesn't that mean that nothing you do matters?
这是什么意思?听着 兄弟 我正和我最好的朋友坐在一起 想帮他度过难关
What does that mean? Look, brother, I am sitting here with my best friend, trying to help him get through a tough time.
对吧?就算我没真实存在 这些时刻仍然是真的
Right? And even if I'm not real, this moment is.
此时 此地 的这一刻是真的
Right here, right now. This moment is real.
有什么比试图帮助自己爱的人更真呢?
I mean, what's more real than a person tryin' to help someone they love?
如果那都不真实 我就真不知道什么是真的了
Now, if that's not real, I don't know what is.
你认识其他警卫吗?
Do you know the other security guards?
全都认识 干嘛问这个?
I know 'em all. Why?
巴迪 别有不错的一天... 要有很好的一天
Hey, Buddy... let's not have a good day... let's have a great day.
盖伊 我们来这干什么?
Guy, what are we doin' here?
把一个短片拿给我朋友 米莉
We're here to get a video clip for my friend Millie.
这看起来够吓人吗?
Does this look intimidating?
我不知道 盖伊 这要怎么握?
I don't know, Guy. How do you hold this thing?
你手上有我要的东西
You have something I want.
你得把它交出来
And you're gonna hand it over.
你怎么进来的?
How'd you get in here?
放轻松...我认识你的警卫
Easy. I know your security guard.
吉米?
Jimmy?
他叫卢吉
His name is Luigi.
你花点时间认识他...他背叛你之前说不定还会犹豫一下
So if you took some time to learn his name... maybe he wouldn't turn on you so quick.
我需要一段影片 交出来
I need a video clip, and you're gonna give it to me.
等一下 你是…你是"蓝衫哥"吗?
Wait a minute, are you... Are you Blue Shirt Guy?
对 大概吧
Yeah, maybe.
我靠 你是盖伊!你是"蓝衫哥"!是你
Holy shit! You're Guy! You're Blue Shirt Guy! It's you!
是没错... -我太爱你了
- Yeah. - I love you.
你认真?  -我……我是你的狂粉 你真的好赞
- You do? - I mean... I'm like a fan. You're awesome.
想要什么我都给你
You can have anything you want.
等等 等一下
Wait, hold on one second.
游戏玩家们 听好了 我是"复仇杰明之按钮哥"
Gamers, listen up, this is Revenjamin Buttons here.
我和盖伊在一起
I'm here with Guy.
盖伊在我的藏身处 准备来抢劫我了
The Guy, he's in my stash house, and he's here to rob me.
盖伊 能给我的粉丝们点"什么?什么?"吗? -什么?
Can I get a little... - "what-what" for my followers, Guy? - What?
太完美了，现在的情况是盖伊在找一个短片
Perfect. All right, so what's happening is... Guy's looking for a clip...
里面就是进入秘密关卡的秘诀
showing a walkthrough I did to get to the secret level.
你在跟谁说话?
Who are you talking to?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我在跟谁说话? 这个也很盖伊
Who am I talking to? It's just such a classic Guy line.
对吧?
Right?
你很好 不管了… 而你 你想用那个叫莫洛托夫的小妞从我这里偷走它
You're good. Oh, anyway... And you, you tried to steal it from me with that Molotov chick.
她的名字是米莉
Her name's Millie.
是的...等等，谁? -米莉
- Yeah. Wait, who? - Millie.
进展得挺顺利的
I think it's going really well.
我知道 我第一次把枪拿出来耶
I know. This is literally the first time I took my gun out the holster.
真的 是不是?
Totally. Right?
盖伊 我试着回去 但漏洞已经被修补了
Guy, I tried to go back through, but the glitch is patched.
我找不到了
And I never found it again.
所以我是唯一见过另一端的人
So I'm the only one that ever saw what was on the other side.
但纪录在里面 你看
But it's all here, check it out.
其实挺酷 像是另一个完整的世界
It's pretty cool actually. It's like a whole other world.
就这样?这是游戏剪辑? -对 就这样
- This is it? This is the game clip? - Yeah, that's it.
你能帮我一件 就一件
Can you do one, single, just one solid for me?
一件事 我就不会再问了 可以吗? -好吧
- One thing, I'll stop asking, okay? - Yeah.
说出我的口号
Just say my catchphrase.
那会让我的观众陷入疯狂 疯狂把香蕉奶油三明治涂在自己身上
My viewers will just banana cream sandwich all over themselves if you say it.
我喜欢香蕉奶油三明治
I love banana cream sandwiches.
也许不是这个香蕉奶油三明治
Maybe not this banana cream sandwich.
是啊 是这个
Yeah, this one.
好的 很棒。那请说"你知道现在几点了吗"
Okay, perfect. Okay, so just say, "You know what time it is?"
你知道现在什么时候了吗? -你知道现在什么时候了吗?
You know what time it is? - You know what time it is?
你知道现在什么时候了吗?
You know what time it is?
现在是犯罪的时候 宝贝 没错
It's crime o'clock, baby. Yeah.
现在是犯罪…… 不 我不能这么说 这是…… -没关系 我自己说
It's crime o'cl... But, no, I can't say that. That's... -Okay. It's all right. I'll say it myself.
好吧 你知道现在什么时候了吗? -不
All right, you know what time it is? - No.
现在是犯罪…… 妈!
It's crime o'cl... Mom!
妈! 你认真吗 现在吸地?
Mom! Are you serious with the... vacuum right now?
非得在这里吗?我正在喊口号!大家都在看耶
You really have to do that here? I'm saying my... catchphrase! Everybody's watching!
上帝阿! -你都22岁了还赖在家里 上帝在这里不存在啦
- God! - You're 22, living in my house, there is no God!
对不起 盖伊
Sorry, Guy.
谢谢你 按钮哥 我们要走了
Thank you, Mr. Buttons. We're gonna go.
不,不,不!不 你得杀了我
No, no, no! No, you gotta kill me.
抱歉 你说什么? -你得杀了我 请杀了我
I'm sorry, what? - You gotta kill me. Please kill me.
请射过来 爸爸 请射过来
Give it to me, Daddy. Give it to me!
拜托 别这样 请别这样
No. Please don't do that. Please don't do that.
我们不会伤害任何人 我是好人
We're not gonna hurt anybody. I'm a good guy.
什么?你刚说什么?
What? What'd you say?
这好深
That's deep.
不 不深
No, it's not.
感觉能深深地尝到你的味道
That's like I can taste you, deep.
我需要你的帮助 兄弟 我没有密码
I want your help, Buddy. I don't have the safeword.
我知道你需要什么
I know what you want.
不是你想的那样
I don't want that.
是 你就想那样
Yeah, you do.
真是感人
That's touching.
下面他们开始"感受"了 -好的
They're touching. - Yeah.
我知道你想要什么
I know what you want.
没错 我知道
Yes, I do.
你想要品尝一下自由城的激情
You want a little bit of that Free City Itchy Kitty.
才没有 -有 你有
No. - Uh-huh. Yes, you do.
你的动作 超级脏的
The way you move, it's almost dirty.
把灭霸手套换成灭霸摆腰怎么样?
What about a little Thanos Glove... into a little bit of Thanos Snap?
哦 看起来很疼 -有一点
Oh. That looked like it hurt. - Yeah, a little bit.
周末老司机日
A little Sunday Drive.
你家很漂亮
You have a beautiful home.
猛蛇入洞呢?不猛蛇入洞吗? -掰掰 按钮哥
Snakey Man? No? No Snakey Man? - Bye, Mr. Buttons.
来吧 给我猛蛇嘛! 就来嘛 兄弟
Come on, give me one snake! Just come on, man.
妈妈!别碰那支袜子
Mom! Do not touch that sock!
我对天发誓 如果你敢碰那支袜子...你余生得在医院度过了
I swear to God, if you touch that sock... you will be in therapy for the rest of your life!
不!那是我的特殊款袜子!放下
No! That's my special sock! Put it down!
米莉
Millie, please.
拜托你醒来
Please wake up from your standing coma.
我知道这个世界对你而言 只是个来去自如的游戏
Look, I know this world is just a game to you and you can come and go,
但对我来说… 这地方 这些人 是我拥有的一切
but to me... this place, these people, that's all I have.
如果我能帮你拯救这世界 我想这样…… 但你得醒醒 求你了
And if I can help you save it, I wanna do that... but you gotta wake up, please.
米莉 很抱歉我逃走了
Millie, I'm sorry for running away.
盖伊?
Guy?
哦 太可怕了! 真的好可怕
Oh, that's so scary! It's just terrifying.
我知道 我知道
I know, I know.
对不起 对不起
I'm sorry, I'm sorry.
听着 你大概从小就只能当背景人物 但其实我也是
Look, you may have started out living in the background, but so did I.
我们别再忍受了
We're done with that.
我给你带了个礼物
I got you a present.
我没时间包装起来
I didn't have time to wrap it.
什么?
What?
据说每年有成千上万个非玩家角色被杀死
They say over a billion NPCs are killed every year.
恩..老实说 至少一半是我做的
Now, I'm not gonna lie, that's at least 50% my fault.
以前我对任何配角都没在客气的 懂我意思吗?
I used to shoot all the secondary characters when I was bored, you know?
先射死再慢慢戏谑
And then, I'd teabag 'em a little bit.
谁知道这个"蓝衫哥"是谁
Who the hell even knows who this Blue Shirt Guy is?
但我得承认 他逼得我开始思考
But I'll tell you this, he's got me thinkin'
非玩家角色是不是会影响我的游玩方式
about NPCs and how I play the game.
这游戏不是为这种人设计的 不是给玩家当滥好人
The game wasn't even made for someone like this, for a player to be a good guy.
他好可爱
He's also a really cute guy.
不只有脸 你知道吗 全部都好可爱
And not just the face, you know, like the whole thing.
其实我渐渐开始觉得我们对非玩家角色有些误解
And, honestly, it's got me realizing... maybe we've been thinking about NPCs wrong this whole time.
我觉得"蓝衫哥"像个象征
I think Blue Shirt Guy's like a symbol, you know?
人们可以成为自己想成为的任何人
Like, maybe people can be whatever they want.
他就像一个"标章"...这词对吗?
He's like an icon. Is that the right word?
告诉我们这世界有无限可能
Like, he reminds us of what's possible.
还有 他真的超性感
Also, he's like crazy hot.
哦 天哪 完全正确，我超哈他的
Oh, my God, totally. I'd hit those pixels hard.
我们都应该学学"蓝衫哥"
We should all be more like Blue Shirt Guy.
也许我们该停止互相残杀了
Maybe we just stop the killing.
他完蛋了 听到没?
He's dead! You hear me?
把那个家伙投影上来
The guy, put him up here.
放到荧幕上 放到荧幕上!
Put him up here on the screen. Put him on the screen.
让我看看 就在这里
Make me see him. There he is.
对 就是你 滥好人
Yes. There he is, the little do-gooder.
我以为你喜欢蓝色衬衫
I thought you liked Blue Shirt.
别跟我说话
Don't say words to me!
线上平台围观这个鲁蛇的观众快满出来了
People are so busy watching this loser on Twitch and YouTube.
你知道他们少做了什么吗?
You know what they're not doing, guys?
掏钱买续作
Buying Free City 2.
预售人数下降了16%... - 是60%
Pre-sales are down 16%. - 60.
真遭
60. That's bad.
距离发表还有48小时
Oh, we are 48 hours from launch.
他像瘟疫般疯狂流传爆红
Yeah, he's gone viral.
是啊 一种让我屁股和蛋蛋都得癌症的病毒
Yeah, a virus that's giving me ass and ball cancer at the same time!
还割不掉!
Inoperable!
你知道 这种好人的套路会对游戏 整个系列造成负面影响
You know, this whole good guy routine... it is a bad influence, and is bad for the franchise.
我要他滚蛋 我不管他是谁 踢掉他
I want him gone. I don't care who it is, boot him.
你不可以
You can't.
哦 对不起 你说什么?
Oh, I'm sorry, what?
你不能
You can't.
为什么不行呢?
Why not?
因为他不是骇客 安托万 他是非玩家角色
Because he's not a hacker, Antwan. He's an NPC.
你是想表达 非玩家角色有自我意识的这套屁话是真的?
You're tryin' to tell me that all this shit about a self-aware NPC is real?
是的 我不知道发生了什么事 但他是真的
Yeah. I don't know how or why, but he's real.
我该怎么办?我该怎么办?
What am I gonna do? What am I gonna do?
好吧 好吧 好吧
Okay, okay, okay, okay, okay.
怎么办..怎么办.. 有了
What to do? What to do? Got it.
跳
And kip-up!
我们不能把他踢出游戏
So we can't kick him out of the game.
那我们怎么重设他的人工智慧? 各位 动脑 拿出主意
How do we reset his AI? Ideas, people. Come on.
告诉我 来点想法
Hit me. Ideas.
你可以重新启动伺服器
You could just reboot the server.
继续说
Keep talking.
如果我们重启伺服器...他就会变成一个普通的非玩家
If we reboot the server... then he's just gonna revert back to a regular non-player guy.
这就是解决方案 -安托万
Solution. - Antwan.
安托万 那可是首次被确认有生命的人工智慧
Antwan, you're talking about terminating... the first confirmed artificially intelligent life-form right now, okay?
亲爱的 亲爱的 嘘
Honey, honey. Shush.
他让我损失越来越多
He's losing me money.
所以 我才不管他是不是该死的阿诺史瓦辛德
So, I don't care if he's Arnold-Frickin'- Schwarzen-Vader.
终结他 重启
Terminate him. Reboot.
这就去 -你不能这么做
- On it. - You can't do that.
重启
Reboot!
"点一杯嗜血狂汁淹来满足你的欲望"
Order up and drown your bloodlust... with a tall glass of murder juice.
"本周的精彩节录"
Here's this week's highlights.
他很懂的表现自我
He's very expressive with his body.
显而易见
Clearly.
那是什么?
What is that?
那边是一个全新的世界
It's a whole new world over there.
有点像天堂之类的
Some kinda paradise and shit.
我的天啊 就是那个
Oh, my God, that's it.
这是我们的源代码 能证明我们存在于游戏里
It's our original build and that build is proof our code is in the game.
你不知道我等此刻等了多久
You have no idea how long I've waited for this.
我看过这里
I've seen this place.
什么?
What?
是的
Yeah.
什么意思?你怎么可能看过?
What do you mean? How could you have possibly seen it?
米莉吗?米莉吗?
Millie? Millie?
我们是黑暗 自由之城已经下线
We're dark. Free City is offline.
搞啥阿?
What is happening?
再见 小蓝衫
Bye-bye, Blue Shirt.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
没关系 来吧
It's okay. Come on.
来吧
Come on.
快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on.
早安阿 小金
Good morning, Goldie.
干燥而温煦的火药味中夹杂着午后太阳的热情
Front of warm, dry gunfire... mixed with late afternoon stabbings...
可能会让你殒命街头 成为周二午后血红色的点缀
could leave you in the streets wet with the blood of innocents... by early Tuesday night.
浅焙和深焙的差在哪里?
What really is the difference between a light roast and a dark roast?
谁知道
Nobody knows.
别有不错的一天... 要有很好的一天
Don't have a good day, have a great day.
盖伊 我们能谈谈吗?
Guy, can we talk?
那墨镜女孩怎么知道你的名字?
How does the sunglass girl know your name?
我不知道 一直走
I don't know. Keep walking.
来吧 盖伊!你认识我
Come on, Guy! You know me.
你知道的
You know this.
你说你曾看过这段影片里某个地点
You said this clip showed a place you'd seen before.
告诉我在哪里
I need to know where.
数据被删除了 但你脑子里的还在
The data's been erased, but it's in your head.
拜托回想一下 这真的很重要
Please try to remember. This is really important.
拜托 盖伊 想一下...冰淇淋 秋千?
Please, Guy, think. The ice cream, the swings?
我的盖伊超爱荡秋千
Oh, my Guy loves swings.
自由城的港边公园 有一个很棒的秋千
At Free City Harbor Park, there's a great swing set there.
你去过吗? -有
Have you been? - Yes.
我们吃了泡泡糖冰淇淋
We had bubble gum ice cream.
我的天 我喜欢泡泡糖冰淇淋
OMG, I love bubble gum ice cream!
他喜欢泡泡糖冰淇淋
He loves the bubble gum ice cream.
我知道 我们一起去过 记得吗?
Yes, I know. We had it together, remember?
求你了 盖伊 你是我的一切
Please, Guy, you're all I've got.
抱歉 女士 你应该找错人了
I'm sorry, lady. I think you have the wrong guy.
别有不错的一天... 要有很好的一天
Don't have a good day, have a great day.
喂?
Hello?
我发现了点东西
I might've found something.
我一直在检查盖伊的编码 删除后竟然还有留下一点东西
I've been going through Guy's code and there is something there... even now, after the wipe.
重点是什么?
What's the point?
盖伊是个奇蹟 是十亿分之一的机率 复制不来的
Guy was, like, a one-in-a-billion miracle. We can't replicate that.
我试过了 好吗?你是对的 一切都结束了
I tried, okay? You were right, it's over.
不 米莉 米莉 你没听明白
No, Millie, Millie, you're not listening to me, all right?
重新启动不能清除他的人工智慧...必须摧毁整个伺服器才能
A reboot, it doesn't erase his AI coding... you literally would have to destroy the servers to do that.
他的人工智慧还在 但是需要去存取他
His AI is still there, it just needs to be accessed.
我见了他 键盘 他全忘了
I've seen him, Keys. He's forgotten everything.
去看我发给你的纪录日志
Just look at the trace log I sent you.
那能解释一切
It'll explain everything.
我们的源代码造成盖伊的行为从一开始就复杂得多
Now, from the beginning... Guy's behavior is much more complex than it should be, thanks to our code.
但他还困在自由城里 还困在无限循环里
But he's still stuck in Free City. He's still stuck in this life, this loop.
突然有某些变化让他活了起来 是什么原因?
And then, something changes. He comes to life. Why?
然后我想起来
And then I remembered.
我在《生活本身》中创了一个角色，就是他，我取名作"失恋王者"
One of the characters from Life Itself was this guy that I nicknamed Lovelorn.
他一辈子注定遇不上真命天女
And he was someone who was designed to never meet the right person.
这是角色天生的限制
It was essentially the building blocks of the character.
但他从未停止寻找梦中情人
But he never stopped hoping that he would meet "the girl of his dreams."
所以我得基于某个女孩为原型打造出新角色 没有人选比我朝夕相处的人更好了
So I had to base this girl off of someone... and who better than the person that I was sitting next to every day?
就是你
You.
他遇见你的那天 他变了
But then, one day... he meets you in Free City, and once he sees you... he can never be the same.
他本来应该感受到命中注定 但是他却感受到了生命 然后就真的活了起来
He was supposed to feel doomed, but instead, he feels alive... until eventually, he is alive.
你改变了他 米莉
You changed him, Millie.
你改了他的程式 我觉你这次也能做到
You changed his code. And I think you can do it again.
你让他活过来了 米莉
You brought him to life, Millie.
你让他复活了
You brought him to life.
他活着唯一的原因就是遇见了你…
And he was alive because he met the one person....
别有不错的一天... 要有很好的一天
Don't have a good day... have a great day.
谢谢你
Thank you.
慢走
Take care.
所有人都趴下!
Everybody down on the ground!
别逞英雄的话 很快就能结束
Nobody try to be a hero. This will all be over soon.
好吧
Okay.
每个人除了你
Everybody except you.
门!门!门! 我打开了
Door, door, door. I got it.
求你 我家里还有条金鱼
Please, I have a goldfish.
听好 我时间不多
Look, I don't have long.
因为绑架你 我头上多了三枚徽章
I just took you hostage, so there are three badges on me.
徽章?那是啥?这是什么女童子军活动吗?
Badges? Is that like a Girl Scout thing? What is that?
你身体里面有东西 盖伊
There is something inside you, Guy.
什么?我不想让任何东西进入我
What? I don't want anything inside of me.
他们把你困在银行里 希望你遵守规则…-我喜欢银行啊
They stuck you in that bank and... expected you to just follow the rules... - I love the bank.
...每天做同样的事情
...and do the same thing every day.
你的世界远不止如此
You are so much more than that.
我不想再干嘛了
I don't wanna be more than that.
不 我要你记住
No, and I need you to remember it.
为什么跟踪我?还有你怎么知道我的名字?
Why have you been following me and how do you know my name?
穿上
Put these on.
我不用被迫做不喜欢的事
I don't have to do anything that I don't wanna do.
没错 你完全能选择
True. The choice is totally yours.
好吧 好吧 很好
Okay. Okay. Fine.
那什么?
What is that?
这是什么?魔术眼镜之类的?
What are these? Trick glasses or something?
仔细倾听
Listen carefully.
24小时后 这个世界、你所认识的人 将会永远消失
In 24 hours, this world, everyone you know, it's all gonna disappear for good.
能放我走吗?
Can you please just let me go?
我真的不知道你是谁
I mean, I haven't really even seen your face.
我看大概知道 但我不太擅长描述
I mean, I've seen the general area, but I'm not really good with descriptive words.
我真不善言辞
Not really good with words in general.
去他的 -什么?哦
Screw it. - What? Oh!
我回想起来了
I remember.
欢迎回来
Welcome back.
我想起一切了
No. I remember everything.
跟我来
Come with me.
我每天都这么做 都忘了为什么了
I do this every day so much, I'd forgotten why.
看到了吗?
Do you see that?
在这里
Right there.
哦 我的天
Oh, my God.
哦 我的天啊
Oh, my God!
安托万把源代码藏在地平线背面 但他忘了删除反光
Antwan hid our original build past the horizon, making it invisible... but he forgot to scrub the reflections.
它还在外面 盖伊 我们只是看不见而已
It's still out there, Guy. We just can't see it.
如果我们能做到 那就是我们需要的证据
If we can get there, that is the evidence we need.
你没法越过水 我试过了
You can't go past the water line. I tried.
我们需要帮忙
We need help.
安托万把它藏在了一个没人能到达的地方
Antwan found a way to hide it in plain sight in the one place no one can even get to.
不敢相信他有这么聪明，干的出这种事
I can't even believe he's smart enough to be this diabolical.
键盘 我需要你集中精神
Keys, I need you to focus.
好吧 所以 反射的画面显示出源代码跨越了南部地平线
Okay. So, the reflection shows the build past the southern horizon.
但物理引擎会限制你跨越海滩
But the game physics won't allow you past the beach.
你能找到办法让我们穿过防撞网吗?
But you think you can find a way to get us past the collision mesh?
我们需要一座桥
We're gonna need a bridge.
你先去杀手海滩 剩下的我来解决
You just get to Hitman's Beach and I'll figure out the rest.
米莉?
And, Millie?
小心
Be careful.
安托万也许是个混蛋 但他不蠢
Antwan may be an asshole, but he's not stupid.
他会发现你的目的 对你投下一切的阻碍
He'll figure out what you're up to and he'll throw everything he's got at you.
你说的对
You're right.
嗨 米莉 和那个我看不见的人… 我有个主意
Um, hi, Millie, and other person I can't see... well, I have an idea.
如果他没有东西可以扔呢?
What if he has nothing to throw?
所有人!集合!
Everyone! Gather around!
谢谢你们的到来
Thank you for coming.
现在大家都认识我了 我叫盖伊
Now, you know me, I'm Guy.
嗨 盖伊
Hi, Guy.
嗨
Hi.
我接下来要说的话可能很难理解
What I'm about to say may be hard to understand.
真的很难理解
Really hard to understand.
但是 你是否厌倦了生活在幕后?
But, are you sick of living in the background?
你们难道不讨厌被人开枪吗?
Aren't you sick of being shot at?
受够了
Enough.
被绑架?-不要了
- Taken hostage? - No more.
逃命?-我们受够了
- Run over? - We done with that.
被抢劫呢?被捅?被当人肉盾牌?
Robbed? Stabbed? Used as a human shield?
我们厌倦了被捅
We are tired of being stabbed!
巴迪! -不好意思
- Buddy! - Sorry.
你想表达什么 盖伊?
What are you trying to say, Guy?
我想说的是 在这座城市里 事情不用变这样子的
I'm tryin' to say that things in this city don't have to be this way.
我们可以不一样的
Things can be different.
怎样不一样?
Different how?
首先 你可以放下你的手 -好
- For starters, you can put your arms down. - Yeah.
继续 你抓到诀窍了 继续
There you go. You got it. Yeah.
继续努力 没错
Keep pushing. There you go.
一边呼吸 很好
Breathe through it. There you go.
放下 放下 放下
Do it. Do it. Do it.
不 不可能 不
No, not gonna happen. Nope.
这感觉很不自然
That feels unnatural.
如果有人拿枪出现怎么办?
I mean, what about when someone runs in with a gun?
举手投降简单又省时
Having my arms up is just a real time saver.
但是 如果拿枪的人不来了怎么办?
Except, what if the guy with the gun doesn't come?
什么?-什么?
What? - What?
拿枪的人永远都在
There's always a guy with a gun.
到处都有拿枪的人
So many guys with guns.
各位 如果我们的世界没必要这么恐怖呢?
People, what if our world doesn't have to be so scary?
如果我们能改变它呢?
What if we can change it?
米莉!在你的世界里 银行一天被抢劫几次?
Millie! How many times a day are the banks robbed in your world?
趋近于零
Hardly ever, Guy.
那死人呢 米莉?
What about corpses, Millie?
什么?-你见过很多死人吗?
- What? - You see a lot of those?
一个小时死几人?
How many an hour?
半个人都没有 盖伊
None per hour, Guy.
那么枪支暴力呢?
What about gun violence?
在你的世界枪支暴力严重吗?
See a lot of gun violence in your world?
其实满严重的 盖伊 满严重的
Actually, that's a big problem, Guy. It's a massive problem.
这样接不下去
I didn't see that coming.
是真的 糟透了
It's true. It really sucks.
重点是 我们不需要成为自己生活的旁观者
The point is, we don't have to be spectators to our own lives.
我们想做什么就做什么
We can be whatever we want.
我们不可能都成为你 盖伊
We can't all be you, Guy.
那不是真的
That's not true.
我体内的东西也在你体内
What's inside of me is inside of you, too.
什么?
What?
它在你们每个人的内心里成长
It's inside of each and every one of you. You're growing.
我不仅想泡滴滤咖啡 我想做…卡布奇诺
I need more in my life than drip coffee. I want to make... A cappuccino.
真是天壤之别
A goddamn difference in the world.
得更好
Much, much better.
一杯珍珠绿茶
And a green tea boba.
天啊!-这是正确的
- Holy shit! - That's right!
勇敢去做吧 女孩
You go, girl.
天啊 你太神奇了
Oh, my God, you're amazing!
如果我能游过那片水域 将会有一个自由的世界等着我们
If I could just make it out past that water... there's a world out there where we can be free.
我们可以决定自己想成为什么样的人
Where we get to decide who we wanna be.
我们可以发挥影响力 但我们必须勇敢争取
Where we can matter. But we have to fight for it.
我们必须一起奋斗
We have to fight together.
对!
Yeah!
你们一直都在做你们该做的事
You guys have always done what's expected of you.
但该到此为止了
But that shit ends today.
是啊
Yeah!
我甚至没搞清楚现在发生什么事
I don't even know what's happening right now!
但我喜欢!
But I love it!
我喜欢!
I love it!
我也喜欢!来吧 伙伴们 都过来
I love it, too! Come on, guys, get in here!
聚过来!这就是我们的目标!一起加入吧
Huddle up! Here's what we're gonna do! Everyone in!
所有人趴下
Everybody get down on the ground!
哈罗?
Hello?
大家去哪了?
Where the hell is everybody?
哈罗?
Hello?
那些非玩家角色去哪了?
Where are all the NPCs?
听着 我玩自由之城将近三年了
Look, I've been playing Free City for, like, three years now.
我从来没见过这种事
I've never seen anything like this.
在这以前 我根本不会注意到有什么NPC消失
Up until recently, I don't even know if I'd have noticed a few NPCs going missing.
乡民论坛流传着一个疯狂的理论
And I don't know if this is just some whack Reddit theory...
有人说"蓝衫哥"根本就不是玩家
but some people are saying that Blue Shirt Guy isn't even a player.
他是人工智慧-人工智慧?
That he's actual AI. - AI?
真实的人工智慧 你知道 活生生的
Actual AI. You know, alive.
所以"蓝衫哥"才会风靡四处
It's why Blue Shirt Guy is trending everywhere.
安托万 如果你有在看 请修复漏洞
Antwan, if you're watching this, please fix the game.
最重要的是 把"蓝衫哥"带回来 -我的天啊 我的天啊
- And most of all, bring back Blue Shirt. - Oh, my God. My God!
安托万 你得看看这个
Antwan, you should see this.
而你 你想利用那个叫莫洛托夫的小妞把它偷走
And you, you tried to steal it from me with that Molotov chick.
她叫米莉 -谁?
Her name's Millie. - Who?
米莉
Millie.
找到她了 找到她了!抓到你了!抓到你了
Got her. Got her! Got you! Got you!
鼠标 把他投影到大画面 快
Mouser! Put him up on the screen. Now. Put him up.
对了 来 快点儿
That's it. Come on, quicker.
是的 他在那儿
Yes, there he is.
他和一个叫莫洛托夫的玩家在自由城兜风
He's joyriding around Free City with some player called Molotovgirl.
又名米莉·拉斯科?
AKA Millie Rusk.
米莉·拉斯科?那不是键盘的老搭档吗?
Millie Rusk? Isn't that Keys' old partner?
是的
Yeah.
她还想和我打诉讼 因为她非常想要有关淳美的那部分程式
Also the one who's trying to hit me with this bogus lawsuit... 'cause she's desperate for a piece of Soonami Kwan.
现在启动莫洛托夫
Boot Molotovgirl now.
我正在试 但她的帐号有保护机制
I'm trying. I'm trying as hard as I can, but her account's spoofed.
这个女人很特别
This woman is exceptional.
那就在游戏里杀了她
Then kill her in the game.
什么? 对 我说了 杀了她
"What?" Yes, I said that. Kill her.
把所有东西丢过去 给她5个徽章
Throw everything at them, all right? Five badges, G.
可以 只有一个问题
Yeah, just one problem.
我们手上空无一物
We don't have anything.
你在说什么 威利斯?
Whatchu talking about, Willis?
我们没有任何防御措施
We don't have any defenses.
我们没有警察 军队 什么都没有
We don't have police, military, no nothing.
这就是我一直想告诉你的
It's what I've been trying to tell you.
每个非玩家角色都在罢工
It's like every NPC went on strike.
一大杯 半咖啡 双层泡沫燕麦奶 肉桂抹茶拿铁
Got a tall, half-caf, double foam oat milk, matcha latte with cinnamon!
那是我的 -嗨
That's me. - Hey.
谢谢 -不客气
Thank you. - You're welcome.
干杯
Cheers.
去抓住他们 盖伊
Go get 'em, Guy!
好像一场数位罢工
It's like a digital walkout.
不 并不是
No, it's not.
他们有其他目的 这只是计划的冰山一角
They're doing this on purpose, it's part of their plan.
你知道我们要做什么吗? 要在游戏中干掉他们
You know what we're gonna do? We're gonna kill them in the game.
关掉重生机制 杀了他们
Turn off respawn, kill them dead, now.
但这也会同时终结所有玩家
But that means any players who die will be done for good.
他们会吓死
They'll freak out.
我不在乎
I don't care.
长官? 讲清楚点 你是说我们要被辞职了吗?
Sir? Sir, just to be clear, are you telling me that it's go time?
你想自找没趣?你以为我们是朋友 是什么 互助会吗?
Are you looking for some sort of banter thing 'cause you think we're friends now... and we're in some sort of gang together?
是的 是的 这就是我想要的
Yes. Yes, that's exactly what I'm looking for.
很好 我们是一个团队
Cool, we're a team.
我们应该想一个口号 好不好?-好的
We should come up - with a catchphrase, okay? - All right.
数到三 一 二 三……  -一 二 三…滚回去工作!
On three. One, two, three... - One, two, three... Get back to work!
谁把键盘叫过来!
Someone find me Keys!
好了 大家都听到了 是时候走人了
All right, people, you heard him. It's go time!
这...这可不妙
Okay, that's not good.
他知道我们要去哪里
He knows where we're going.
没问题 我控制住他了 控制住他了 别担心
All right, I got him. I got him. Don't worry.
想要轮胎赏脸吗?
Want some four wheels to the face?
接招吧
Take that. Boom!
顶端掠食者 兔子来找你了
Rabbit's coming for you. Apex predator.
哇
Whoa!
快结束了 你各位有看清楚吗?
Here we go. Y'all watching this?
我快终结这个傻瓜了
I'm about to end this fool.
快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on.
键盘 如果你听到到 拜托帮帮忙
Keys, if you're there, a little help, please.
天阿!马上来 谁干的?谁在搞这些?
God! Okay, who did that? Who is doing that?
别想跟我对着干 我认真起来谁都怕
Don't play with me! Seriously! I'm under way too much pressure!
来吧
Come on!
加速 加速 加速!
Go, go, go!
刚跟保全确认过 键盘还在这栋楼里
I just checked with security. Keys hasn't left the building.
听起来你已经尽力了
Oh, sounds like you've done everything possible.
是时候放弃了?你想放弃吗?
Time to give up? You wanna give up?
不 我觉得你希望我继续找
No, I'm sensing you want me to keep looking.
走吧 -我会回来的
Go. - I'll be back.
不知道这几个蠢蛋要开去哪
I have no idea where these fools are running to.
我知道 南海岸 杀手海滩
I do. Southern shore. Hitman's Beach.
那也太愚蠢了 那里除了水啥都没有
Well, that's stupid. There's nothing out there but water.
物理引擎也不可能让你通过海岸线
Game physics won't even let you get past the shoreline.
除非外面还有什么东西
Unless there is something out there.
安托万 外面还有什么吗?
Antwan, is there something there?
去他的 美术怪咖
Screw it. Art nerds.
该让"大家伙"上场了
Time for Dude.
我们还没设计好
We're still working on him.
他是我亲自设计的 完美无缺
I worked on him myself. He's perfect.
立刻下放他
Drop in Dude now.
做就对了 只是他只有半颗脑子...勉强..上传吧
Just do it. He's got, like, half a brain... he's barely written, but sure, start the upload.
现在该怎么办?
What are we supposed to do now?
键盘帮我们找了一座桥
Now Keys finds us a bridge.
你是来取回捅在我背上的刀子的吗 兄弟?
Come to collect those knives you stabbed in my back, bro?
你一直在帮米莉·拉斯科
You've been helping Millie Rusk this whole time.
她在找你的源代码
She's looking for your build.
什么源代码? 安托万?
What build, Antwan?
你也没用我们的程式码啊 对吧?
It's not like you used our code anyway, right?
如果你没有使用我们的代码 那么我们的源代码又怎么可能出现在游戏里呢?
And if you didn't use our code... then how can our original build be in the game, right?
还是我错过了什么?
Or am I missing something?
出去
Leave us.
好了 键盘 该认真谈了
Okay, Keys, let's have a real talk.
如果我把你的烂游戏发布出去 肯定会失败
If I'd put out your dumb game, it would have bombed.
安托万 你怎么知道会失败
Antwan, you don't know it would've failed.
是的 我知道
Yeah, I do know.
我看了那些数字 追踪记录 焦点讨论
I looked at the numbers, the tracking, the focus groups.
你有没有想过有些东西比数字更重要?
Has it ever occurred to you that some things matter more than numbers?
有什么比数字更重要?钱吗?
What matters more than numbers? Money?
兄弟 钱也是数字
Yo, news flash, bro, money is still numbers.
那没有什么比数字更重要
Nothing matters more than numbers!
你应该感谢我
You should be thanking me!
我该感谢你吗?
I should be thanking you?
你利用我们的成果获利又怎么说?
What about the profits that you got from our work?
队伍是你自选的 小徒儿
You chose your side, little Padawan.
现在 现在你应该站在王者这边
And now, it's time for you to take your place next to the Emperor.
懂我的意思吗 兄弟?
You get me, bro?
是啊 我懂你…兄弟
Yeah, I get you... bro.
这让我想起这个
Which leads me to this.
谢谢 键盘
Thanks, Keys.
那是什么鬼?
What the hell was that?
安托万 事情大条了
Hey, Antwan, things are getting hectic.
我以为你不会这么傻的 键盘
Oh, I thought you were smarter than this, Keys.
你被解雇了 听到没
You're obviously fired, you know that.
还有你 告诉我她还在游戏里干嘛?
And you, what is she still doing in the game, man?
踢出所有人!
Boot everyone.
等等 你要我踢出所有玩家?
Hold up. You want me to boot all the players?
全踢出游戏 现在
Boot them out of the game, now!
删除所有玩家帐号
Cancel every player account!
"大家伙"到底在哪里?
And where the hell is Dude?
警卫!把这家伙带走
Security! Kick this punk out.
盖伊!
Guy!
米莉! -他们正在把我踢出游戏
Millie! - They're taking me out.
发生什么事情了?
What's happening?
现在全靠你了 所有人都靠你了
It's on you now. Everybody's watching.
你必须继续前进
You gotta keep going.
等等 等等 等等!我会再见到你吗?
Wait, wait, wait! Will I see you again?
如果你能越过那座桥 就可以
You will if you make it across that bridge.
向全世界展示我们的源代码 这就是证据
Show the whole world our build. That's the proof.
你这么做 安托万就完了
You do that, Antwan is done.
我会成功的
I'll make it.
什么鬼?
What the hell?
这到底怎么回事
What's going on?
不管了 在解雇之前 轰轰烈烈一次
All right, let's all remember this moment, before we were fired.
哦
Oh!
哇
Wow.
口号
Catchphrase.
口号?
Catchphrase?
什么?我没时间好好想一个
What? I haven't had time to think one up yet.
虽然“口号”作为口号是一个相当酷的口号
Although "catchphrase" as a catchphrase is a pretty cool catchphrase.
哇
Whoa.
起来 盖伊 站起来
Get up, Guy. Get up.
哦 不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no.
盖伊 我来救你了
Guy, I came to save you.
这是谁?-我不知道
Who is this? - I don't know.
他好巨
He's glorious.
他跟你好像 不过是优化版的你
I mean, he's just like you... but way better.
好多了
Way, way better.
谢谢 -不 那不是在夸奖
Thank you. - No, that's not a compliment.
我要是你就不会碰他 巴迪
I wouldn't touch him if I were you, Buddy.
不该碰他是什么意思?
What do you mean you don't think I should touch him?
你不介意吧?
You don't mind this, do you?
因为我也是你的朋友
'Cause I'm your buddy, too.
我想他会打你的
Yeah, I think he's gonna... hit you.
他出拳很用力
He punches so hard.
但他的手是那么柔软
But yet his hands are so soft.
坚强点 -好吧 再见
Be strong. - Okay, bye.
我对他来说轻如鸿毛
Hey, it's like I'm a feather to him.
哟
Whee!
哈哈
Ha-ha!
哦……
Oh...
不 不 不!不
No, no, no! No!
起来 盖伊 起来
Get up, Guy, get up!
游戏时间结束了 口号
Playtime's over. Catchphrase.
我不知道那是什么意思
I don't know what that means.
来吧 伙伴 起来
Come on, man. Get up!
快起来
Get up.
我一生只爱三件事
There are three things I love in life.
踹人屁股 第二个还不知道 第三件事就是这个
Kickin' ass, TBD, third thing here.
噢 哦 妈的
Oof! Oh, shit!
启动致命一击
Activate death blow.
再见了 盖伊
Bye, Guy.
哦 该死 是致命一击
Oh, shit, that's a death blow.
起来!
Get up!
妈妈 他要使用致命一击
Mom, he's coming in with a death blow!
起来 盖伊
Get up, Guy.
哦
Oh.
三小?
What the shit?
太屌了
That was dope.
等等 那是…… -这是一个…是的!那是光剑 大家伙
Hold on. Is that... - That's a... Yes! That's a lightsaber, Dude.
嗯哼
Mm-hmm.
那是光剑吗?-是
Is that a lightsaber? - It is.
哦
Oh!
盖伊
Guy!
是的
Yes!
干的好 就是这样 再站起来 盖伊 加油
Yes! That's right. Get up, Guy. Come on.
就是这样
There you go.
看到那些东西了吗?有没有?
Do you see them all now? Yeah?
嗯 -是不是?
Uh-huh. - Yeah?
是 到处都闪烁着光芒
Yeah, shiny things everywhere.
没错 干的好 去收集他们
Yeah, there you go. Go get it.
很多小点心喔
Just lots of little snacks.
恩 不擅长跳舞 不擅长
Yeah, not a dancer. No.
奔向自由吧 优化版的我
Run free, better me.
我们走吧
Let's go.
要去哪里?
Where are we going?
我们不能让他们过桥
We can't let them get across that bridge.
想和我结束这一切吗?
You wanna finish this out with me?
我根本不知道发生什么事 但我他妈的一定支援你
Look, I don't even know what's going on, but hell yes, I'm with you.
哈哈
Ha-ha!
走吧
Let's go!
安托万 别这样 兄弟
Antwan, come on, man.
来这里做什么?
What are we doing here?
自由之城的伺服器在哪里?
Where are the servers to Free City 1?
不 安托万 你他妈要干什么?
No. Antwan, what the hell are you doing?
如果他们跨越地平线到达源代码 我将会一无所有
If they get past that horizon to the build, I lose everything!
等等 所以你真的偷了他们的程式码
Wait, so you did steal their code.
欢迎进入状况 天才
Welcome to the conversation, genius.
那些伺服器在哪里?
Now, where are those servers?
这里全都是 等等 我在试着理清头绪
It's all of these, but hold on. I'm trying to wrap my head around this.
所有吗?这一个吗?哪一个?
All these? This one? Right, this one?
是的 你是怎么……
Yeah. How did you...
跑!
Run.
安托万
Antwan!
停下来
Stop!
强尼警官!
Officer Johnny!
加油!-加油
Come on! - Come on!
桥和大海在哪个伺服器里?
Which server has the ocean and the rest of the bridge?
我不会告诉你
I'm not gonna tell you.
你会毁了全部
You're just gonna destroy it.
没关系啊 这是我的游戏
Yeah. 'Cause it's my game.
但这并不是你的游戏 这是键盘的游戏
Except it's not. It's Keys' game.
你什么屎都不会
You didn't do shit.
你猜怎么着?键盘是我的孩子
And guess what? Keys is my boy.
警卫
Security!
请带走这位前员工
Please escort this former employee off the premises.
他可以叫你的名字的
He can call you by your real name.
盖伊
Guy!
巴迪!巴迪! -不 不!继续前进
Buddy! Buddy! - No, no! Keep going!
别管我 继续走!
Go without me!
我这一生都在害怕
I've been scared my whole damn life.
但我不再害怕了
But I'm not scared anymore.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不会
I'm not.
这是我一生中最美好的一天
It's been the best day of my life.
你去找到那个源代码
You get to that build.
让他们知道我们非同小可
You show 'em we matter.
那个警卫是个真英雄
That security guard right there was a goddamn hero.
你做到了
You did it!
是的!是的
Yes! Yes!
去你的 安托万 !哇
Suck it, Antwan! Whoo!
安托万 快停停
Antwan, stop!
结束了
It's over.
他做到了
He made it.
让所有人看到了你的源代码
Got your game's original build out there for everyone to see.
打赢官司是没问题了 对吧?
Probably win your lawsuit, huh?
大概没问题了
Looks likely.
酷
Cool.
事情是这样的 朋友 事情是这样的
And here's the thing, bro. Here's the thing.
这里 有你在乎的一切
Right here, I got everything you care about.
自由之城剩下的碎片 你所有的好友 包括你的虚拟男友
The sliver that's left of Free City, all your little background friends... including your digital boyfriend.
最后一个伺服器
Last server.
我只想要我建的世界和人
Look, I just want the world that I built and the people in it.
对安托万有什么好处呢?
What's in it for Antwan?
其他的一切
Everything else.
意思是?讲直接一点
Meaning? Pretend I'm dumb.
你有我们程式码的所有权 所有的利润归你 而我只要自由之城剩下的部分
You have the rights to our code, keep all the profits... just give me what's left of Free City.
让我建立我自己的世界
Let me build my own world from there.
自由之城2呢?自由之城3?
What about Free City 2? Free City 3?
所有的附加产品呢?
And all pursuant spin-offs?
都是你的 只要你放下斧头
All yours. Just put down the axe.
你知道这是愚蠢交易史上最愚蠢的交易 对吧?
You know that this is, like, the dumbest deal in the history of dumb deals, right?
你要放弃数百万美元
I mean, you're talking about giving up millions of dollars.
谁会这么做?
Why would anyone do that?
因为键盘和我做出了很棒的东西
'Cause Keys and I made something great.
我不需要金钱或名誉来证明这一点
And I don't need money or fame to prove that to myself.
我受够了你的游戏 安托万
I'm done playing your game, Antwan.
是时候玩我的了
It's time I played mine.
成交?
Deal?
突发新闻
Popping today and not in a good way.
《Free City 2》的销量持续下滑，因为游戏充满漏洞、延迟严重
Sales for Free City 2 continue to slip... with numerous reports of bugs in the code and lagging online play.
淳美游戏创始人安东万发现自己四面楚歌
Embattled Soonami game founder Antwan Hovachelik finds himself in the crosshairs.
四面楚歌
Crosshairs.
他遭受四面楚歌
He's in the crosshairs and embattled.
我们忙到没有时间庆祝
We're too busy to gloat.
我是受害者!我是受害者
I'm a victim! I'm a victim!
说到忙 刚刚我们的访客量翻了一倍
Speaking of busy, we just doubled the amount of unique visitors we can handle.
这是惊人的
It's amazing.
想不到大家只是想看游戏角色 而不是射他们
Who'd have thought that so many people... would just wanna watch video game characters instead of shoot at them?
嗯…没错 我们成功了
Hmm... Oh, yeah, we did.
耶
Yeah.
你吹牛的时候挺可爱的
You know, you're pretty cute when you brag.
安托万出来了
Antwan out!
与此同时《Free Life》也迅速成为小型独立游戏
Meanwhile, the game Free Life is quickly becoming the little indie that could.
玩家涌入这款观察性质的游戏...
Players are swarming to this observational, fishbowl game...
与独一无二的"蓝衫哥"互动 而他不再是只是背景的虚拟角色
where they interact peacefully with the one and only Blue Shirt Guy... and is now no longer in the background, a digital friend.
哦 嗨 米尔斯…
Uh, hey, Mills...
想和我去喝杯咖啡吗?
Do you wanna come grab a coffee with me?
其实我正要回去游戏里
Actually, I'm gonna jump back into the game.
哦 -咖啡吗?
Oh. - Coffee?
好吧 好啊 听起来不错
Okay. Yeah. Sounds good.
还是我就 给你拿一杯就好
I'll just, uh, grab you one.
哦 键盘  -我知道 中杯咖啡 奶油 加两块糖
Oh, Keys, uh... -I know, medium coffee, cream, two sugars.
对
Yeah.
兰迪 你好 弥尔顿
Hi, Randy. Milton.
嗯
Hmm.
正在想到底何时能再见到你
I was wondering when I'd see you again.
最近过的太疯狂了
Yeah, life has been pretty crazy lately.
你该来这里看看
You should see it in here.
有终身免费的泡泡糖冰淇淋
We're talkin' free bubble gum ice cream for life.
哇
Wow.
嘿 伙计们
Hey, guys.
那个 盖伊...唉 这比我想像中的难多了
Look, Guy... Wow, this is harder than I thought.
我来帮你
Then let me do it for you.
"盖伊"
Guy...
"你很梦幻"
you are dreamy.
"你对蓝色衬衫和五重八度音乐的品味…深深地吸引着我"
Your taste in blue shirts and five-octave musical superstars... it's deeply, deeply attractive to me.
"但我不能一直和你在一起"
But I can't keep spending all my time with you.
"我创造世界 但我没办法在这里生活"
I created this world, but I can't live my life in it.
看到没? 没很难吧?
See? Was that so hard?
那你打算怎么办?
So, what are you gonna do?
做任何我想做的 这一切多亏了你
Anything I want. Thanks to you.
我再也不会困在无限循环里
I'm not stuck in a loop anymore.
你也不会
Neither are you.
我爱你 米莉
I love you, Millie.
也许这是我程式设定好的 但你猜怎么着?
Maybe that is my programming talking, but guess what?
程式也是有人写的
Someone wrote that program.
我就像一封专属于你的情书
I'm just a love letter to you.
作者在外面世界的某处
Somewhere out there is the author.
你让他活起来了 你让他活起来了
You brought him to life. You brought him to life.
他活着的原因就是遇见了那个唯一的人
And he was alive because he met the one person he'd been waiting for his whole life.
我得让它更真实 所以我以你为原型...
And I had to make it realistic, so... I based it off of... you.
他的梦中情人……
The woman of his dreams...
和我梦中情人一样
she was the same as mine.
喜欢泡泡糖 冰淇淋和秋千 还有一个非常可爱但很特别的习惯...
So she liked bubble gum ice cream and swing sets..
总是哼唱玛利亚·凯莉的经典歌曲
and she had this very cute but oddly specific habit... of always humming this classic Mariah Carey track.
她会一直重复
Like, all the time, she would... repeat.
终于!
Finally!
键盘
Keys!
你在…
What are you...
没事吧 小盖伊?
You okay, little guy Guy?
你长得很...一些形容词
You seem adjective.
我很好 很好 那个 你可以放我下来
I'm great. I'm great. You could put me down, by the way.
谢谢你 人真好
Thank you. That was nice.
不 我很好 你很棒 大家伙
No, I'm great. You're great, Dude.
我只是想念曾经那个好朋友
I just miss my best friend.
以前每天都一起走这条路
We used to do the same walk together every day.
只不过他有穿上衣 也能讲出完整的句子
Except he wore a shirt. And could complete a full sentence.
我可以卧推一个句子
I can bench press a sentence.
哈 不是这么一回事的
Yeah, that's totally not the same thing at all.
笑得更厉害了
Harder laughter!
喔 盖伊?
Oh... Guy?
巴迪! -不会吧
- Buddy! - No!
哦 我的天啊!盖伊
Oh, my God! Guy!
巴迪!还以为失去你了
Buddy! I thought I'd lost you!
你没有!
You didn't!
前一分钟 我还在一座桥上疯狂奔跑 想着即将结束的平淡生活
One minute, I'm running on a crazy bridge to nowhere... thinkin' my sweet mundane life is over.
下一分钟 我似乎在飞 像...
The next minute, I'm like in some type of flyin'...
像...某种精灵 然后就扑通一声落入了这片天堂
and some like fairy dust, pixie dust... and then I plopped down into this slice of heaven.
兄弟 我好喜欢这里
Man, I love it here.
其实几天前 我骑到一匹半人马
In fact, a couple of days ago, I rode a centaur.
听起来有点奇怪 我骑了又人又马的东西 总之 我做到了
Now, it might sound weird... I took a piggyback ride on a half-dude and a half-horse... whatever a centaur is, I did it.
我也骑过一个家伙
I rode a dude, too!
友善的姿势
Friendly gesture!
好友善
So friendly!
来吧 拿出你的真心
Come on, bring it in!
要抱抱吗? -我去找你
Are we gonna hug? - I'm coming for you!
不 你待着 我来找你 -没错
No, you're not. I'm coming for you. - Yes, I am!
你要过来! -我要过去
You come here! - I'm coming to you!
我要把你拉过来 我要把你拉过来
I'm reeling you in. I'm reeling you in.
巴迪 我好想你
Buddy, I missed you!
嘿 银行在哪儿?
Hey, so where's the bank?
这里没有银行
There is no bank.
那我们要做什么?
So what do we do?
想做什么都行
Whatever we want.
嘿 朋友们! 嘿 盖伊!
Hey, guys.- Hey, Guy.